这么特别的说明，我们换个方式，聊聊吧
It is such a special note that we change the modality, let's chat
es una nota tan especial que cambiamos la modalidad vamos a charlar
阿根廷国家队历史上最重要的球员之一。
one of the most important players in the history of the Argentine national team.
uno de los jugadores más importantes de la historia de la selección argentina.
在《叮当》中，天使迪玛丽亚。
In Clank, Ángel Di María.
En Clank, Ángel Di María.
欢迎 Ángel Di María，很高兴您来到 Clank。
Welcome Ángel Di María, a pleasure to have you at Clank.
Bienvenido Ángel Di María, un placer tenerte en Clank.
一切进展如何？
How is everything going?
¿Cómo va todo?
我们正在推出这种模式...
We are launching this modality of...
Estrenamos esta modalidad de...
因为在这一天国际足联不再......
because on this date FIFA is no longer...
porque en esta fecha FIFA ya no está...
你并不老，你也不在 AFA 在埃塞萨拥有的土地上。
You are not old, you are not on the property that the AFA owns in Ezeiza.
No estás viejo, no estás en el predio que la AFA posee en Ezeiza.
你并不集中在其他国家，你在里斯本。
you are not concentrated in some other country, you are in Lisbon.
no estás concentrado en algún otro país, estás en Lisboa.
一切进展如何？
How is everything going?
¿Cómo va todo?
很高兴，安赫尔，谢谢你。
A pleasure, Ángel, thank you.
Un placer, Ángel, gracias.
你好，好吧，没什么，非常感谢你停止参与，事实是...
Hello, well, nothing, thank you very much for stopping participating, the truth is that as...
Hola, bueno, nada, muchas gracias por dejar de participar, la verdad que como...
正如我告诉你的，我不久前看了一些，我喜欢它并且也想在那里。
As I told you, I was watching some a while ago and I liked it and wanted to be there too.
Como te dije, hace un rato estuve viendo algunos y me gustó y quería también estar.
事实是……
The truth is that...
La verdad que...
这对我来说是一种荣幸，正如你今天所说的那样，因为
which is a pleasure for me and good as you said today since
que es un placer para mí y bueno como dijiste hoy ya desde
另一方面，在我家，现在很平静，有两天自由活动，与家人一起享受。
On the other hand, from my house, now, calm, two days free, enjoying with my family.
De otro lado, desde mi casa, ahora, tranquilo, dos días libres, disfrutando con mi familia.
好吧，正如我所说，我的头脑也放松了一些。
And well, as I say, I'm also a little more relaxed in my head.
y bueno como digo ya un poco más relajado también de cabeza
那种很好的放松，因为这并不是说你失去了竞争的紧张感，
And that good relaxation, because it's not that you lost competitive tension,
Y ese relax del bueno, porque no es que perdiste tensión competitiva,
它会影响你在球场上的表现，让你感觉自己打得更放松、更放松。
It influences you on the court, you feel like you play looser, more relaxed.
Te influye dentro de la cancha, sentís que jugás más suelto, más relajado.
不，不是因为我的存在方式、我的比赛方式总是一样的。
No, not because my way of being, my way of playing was always the same.
No, no porque mi forma de ser, mi forma de jugar siempre fue la misma.
我不可能改变这一点
It is impossible for me to change this
es imposible que cambie esta
在国家队，或者考虑他们是否召唤我去那里并在俱乐部做好事情。
in the national team or thinking about whether or not they summon me to be there and do things well at the club.
en la selección o pensando en que si me citan o no para estar y hacer las cosas bien en el club.
在俱乐部，我一如既往地尽我所能做事。
At the club I continue to do things to the best of my ability, as always.
En el club sigo haciendo las cosas de lo mejor posible, como siempre.
没有什么，总是在一百，我永远不会改变，那永远不会改变，但是好吧......
And nothing, always at a hundred, I never change, that will never change, but well...
Y nada, siempre al cien, nunca cambio, eso nunca va a cambiar, pero bueno...
不同的是，国际足联日期的这一刻到来了，就像
There is the difference in that this moment of the FIFA date arrives and it is like
está la diferencia en que llega este momento de la fecha FIFA y es como que
我降低了一点分贝，多了一点享受家庭时光。
I lower the decibels a little and enjoy the family a little more.
Bajo un poco los decibeles y disfruto un poco más de la familia.
就在今天，我正在和库蒂谈话，我在那里告诉了他关于……的故事。
Just today I was talking to Cuti, I had told him there about the story that went up about...
Justo hoy estaba hablando con el Cuti, le había comentado ahí la historia que subió de...
来自贝尔格拉诺，他为他制作了一面旗帜。
from Belgrano, who made him a flag.
de Belgrano, que le hizo una bandera.
好吧，我们在那里聊了一会儿，他告诉我他们想念我并且......
And well, we were talking there for a little bit and he told me that they missed me and...
y bueno estuvimos hablando ahí un poco y me decía que me extrañaban y...
是的，我告诉他我也想念他，但我想念日常生活。
And yes, I told him that I missed him too, but I missed everyday life.
Y sí, le dije yo que también lo extrañaba, pero extrañaba el día a día.
不是玩的多，而是...
Not the much playing, the much...
No el tanto jugar, el tanto...
你必须训练，你必须与他们分享时刻。
You have to train, you have to share moments with them.
Hay que entrenar, hay que compartir momentos con ellos.
当我想要的时候，当我觉得是时候了，我就剪掉了
I made the cut just when I wanted to, when I felt it was time
Hice el corte justo cuando quería, cuando sentí que era el momento
表示，但很明显，一个人想念朋友，一个人想念自己……
indicated, but it is obvious that one misses one's friends, one misses oneself...
indicado, pero es obvio que uno extraña los amigos, se extraña...
一个人住在那里的时刻，但其余的就像我感觉和感觉我做了
the moments that one lived there but then the rest is like I felt and feel that I did the
los momentos que uno vivía ahí pero después lo demás es como que sentí y siento que hice el
正确的切割。
the right cut.
el corte justo.
是的，我同意。
Yes, I agree.
Sí, coincido.
现在让我们谈谈你是如何做出这个决定的。
And now let's talk about how you made the decision.
Y ahora vamos a hablar de cómo tomaste la decisión.
但让我们来谈谈你怀念的那一天。
But let's talk a little about that day to day that you miss.
Pero hablemos un poquito de ese día a día que extrañas.
到达时，看到自己处于毕业生旅行模式，因为......
Arriving, seeing yourself in graduate trip mode, because...
Llegar, verse en modo viaje de egresados, porque...
有一个 WhatsApp 群组，我想您已被删除或离开。
There is a WhatsApp group from which I imagine you were removed or you left.
Hay un grupo de Whatsapp del cual me imagino te sacaron o te fuiste.
不，我参与了一切，他们要怎么把我救出来呢？
No, I'm in everything, how are they going to get me out?
No, yo estoy en todo, ¿cómo me van a sacar?
哦，他们没有带你出去！
Oh, they didn't take you out!
¡Ah, no te sacaron!
所以你知道一切。
So you are aware of everything.
O sea que estás al tanto de todo.
是的，也许我们在小组里话不多。
Yes, maybe we don't talk much in the group.
Sí, igual no se habla mucho en el grupo.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
比方说，当一个人说话时，它更加个人化，但在那些群体中......
It's a little more individual, let's say, when one speaks, but in those groups...
Es un poco más individual, digamos, cuando uno habla, pero en esos grupos...
当它们留下来时，它们就留在那里，好吧，如果在某个时候有人必须写点什么，好吧……
As they remain, they remain there and well, if at some point one has to write something, well...
Como que van quedando, van quedando ahí y bueno, si en algún momento uno tiene que escribir algo, pues...
你可以把它完美地发送到那里，然后第一个就可以了
You can send it there perfect then well the first one
puede mandar ahí perfecto entonces bueno la primera la
消息是，除了小活动之外，您还继续参与或继续加入 WhatsApp 群组，但让我们每天谈谈那一天，那是什么样的？
The news is that you continue to participate or continue to be in the WhatsApp group beyond the little activity, but let's talk a little about that day to day, what was it like?
la noticia es que seguís participando o seguís estando en el grupo de Whatsapp más allá de la poca actividad pero hablemos un poquito de ese día a día, ¿cómo era?
你最怀念什么？
What do you miss most?
¿Qué es lo que más extrañás?
数学、谈话……
The math, the talks...
Los mates, las charlas...
他们在谈论什么？
What were they talking about?
¿Qué hablaban?
关于足球的话题比生活还多。
There is more talk about football than life.
Se habla más de fútbol que de la vida.
足球仍然处于幕后。
Football remains in the background.
El fútbol queda en un segundo plano.
不，一直以来都有很多关于足球的话题，因为嗯，有很多话题......
No, there is a lot of talk about football all the time, because well, there is a lot of talk...
No, se habla mucho de fútbol todo el tiempo, porque bueno, se habla mucho...
阿根廷足球、某人在哪里踢球、您在哪里以及正在踢球的时刻。
of Argentine soccer, of where one is playing, of the moments where you are and are playing.
de fútbol argentino, de donde uno está jugando, de los momentos donde estás y estás jugando.
如果没有，人们会想
If not, one wonders
Si no, uno se pregunta
向其中一方询问他的情况以及他为什么不上场以及为什么......
to one or the other about how he is and why he doesn't play and why...
a uno o a otro de cómo está y por qué no juega y por qué...
技术人员，这只是一点点吧？
the technician and this is a bit of it, right?
el técnico y esto es un poco todo, ¿no?
当你们也在远方的时候，当你们聊天或者发消息的时候，
When you are also far away, when you chat or send a message,
Cuando uno también está lejos, cuando charla o se manda mensaje,
他问的不是太多关于足球的事情，而是问家庭怎么样等等。
He doesn't ask so much about football, but rather how the family is and that.
No se pregunta tanto por el fútbol, sino cómo está la familia y eso.
在那里，更多的是关于一个人在俱乐部的表现以及之后的所有事情
is there, it's more about how one is in the club and all those things later
está ahí metido es más el cómo está uno en el club y todas esas cosas después
让很多人回来的是扣篮，即出去训练前的那一刻。
What brings many people back are the dunks, the moments before going out to train.
Lo que se trae a muchos son los mates, los momentos antes de salir a entrenar.
早上起床后，你们已经有聚在一个房间喝马黛茶的习惯了。
in the morning when you get up and you already have the habit of getting together in a room to drink mate.
por la mañana cuando te levantás y ya tenés la costumbre de juntarte en una pieza a tomar mate.
度过那些时光，多好啊，去法庭喝酒吧。
to spend those moments, how good, to go to the court drinking mate too.
de pasar esos momentos, que bueno, el ir a la cancha tomando mate también.
聊天，音乐，那些时刻是人们最怀念的。
chatting, music, those moments are what one misses the most.
charlando, música, esos momentos son los que uno más extraña.
在这些谈判中，大量技术人员被屠杀。
The number of technicians has been massacred in those talks.
La cantidad de técnicos viene a haber masacrado en esas charlas.
看看这个不让我兴奋的王八蛋。
Look at this son of a bitch that doesn't turn me on.
Mirá este hijo de puta que no me pone.
你把我从哪里放出来？
Where do you put me from?
¿De dónde me pone?
它让我像那样玩。
It makes me play like that.
Me hace jugar así.
但是你让他在这样一个团队里，他对你表现得好，对我表现得不好，他有什么问题吗？
But you had him in such a team and he behaved well with you and he behaves badly with me, what's wrong with him?
Pero vos lo tuviste en tal equipo y con vos se portó bien y conmigo se porta mal, ¿qué le pasa?
一切都有。
And there is everything.
Y hay de todo.
什么都有，什么都有。
There is everything, there is everything.
Hay de todo, hay de todo.
那一刻你可以触碰任何人。
You can touch anyone at that moment.
Le puedes tocar a cualquiera en ese momento.
离开的决定是怎样的？
What was the decision to leave like?
¿Cómo fue la decisión de dejar?
2023年比赛很多，更多考虑季后赛、友谊赛。
2023 with many matches, more thinking about playoffs, friendly matches.
el 2023 con muchos partidos, más pensando en eliminatoria, a partidos amistosos.
也来庆祝。
also to celebrate.
también para celebrar.
您已经将 2024 年美洲杯视为...
You had already considered the Copa América 2024 as...
Ya te habías planteado la Copa América 2024 como...
著名的最后一支舞，你是什么时候做出的决定？
the famous last dance, when did you make the decision?
el famoso last dance, ¿cuándo tomaste la decisión?
当世界杯结束时，事实是，是时候了……
When the World Cup ended, the truth was, it was time and...
Cuando terminó el mundial, la verdad, era el momento y...
这是我已经计划好的事情，但我没有……
and it was something that I had already planned a little bit, but I didn't...
y era algo que también ya lo tenía un poco planeado, pero no lo...
我没有感觉到，我觉得我不可能在那里。
I didn't feel it, I didn't feel like I could be there.
No lo sentía, no sentía que podía llegar a ser ahí.
因为我以前没有考虑过它，但这就像……好吧，如果事情进展顺利的话……
because I hadn't been thinking about it before, but it was like something that... And well, if things go well...
porque no lo venía pensando ya antes, sino era como algo que... Y bueno, si las cosas salen bien...
最好离开。
Better to leave.
Mejor dejar.
如果出现问题，我想我也完成了这个循环。
If things go wrong, I think I've completed the cycle too.
Si las cosas salen mal, creo que ya también cumplí el ciclo.
但获胜后就像是继续前进的愿望
but after winning it's like the desire to continue
pero después de ganar es como que las ganas de seguir
时间再长一点，美洲杯也就不远了。
Being a little longer, the Copa América was not far away either.
estando un poco más, la Copa América no faltaba mucho tampoco.
我离那里非常近，但我仍然觉得……
and I was there very close and I still felt like...
y estaba ahí cerquita y todavía me seguía sintiendo en que...
我可以在其中表演，同时也可以帮助孩子们。
in which I could perform and at the same time also help the kids.
en que podía rendir y a la vez también ayudar a los chicos.
也回来了并想赢得自己一席之地的年轻人。
young people who came back too and who want to earn their place.
jóvenes que venían atrás también y que van queriendo ganarse su lugar.
这就是为什么世界杯结束后我开始在家里说
and well that's why it was after the world cup that I started saying at home
y bueno por eso fue después del mundial que empecé a decir en casa
美洲杯已经开始了，美洲杯已经开始了。
The Copa América is already, the Copa América is already.
La Copa América ya está, la Copa América ya está.
所以他们一点一点地问我，每次我问......
And so it was little by little, little by little they asked me and each time I asked...
Y así fue poco a poco, poco a poco me fueron preguntando y cada vez lo iba...
随着实力的增强，他对自己的决定也越来越坚定……
Strengthening more, he became more and more sure of the decision and...
Afianzando más, cada vez estaba más seguro de la decisión y...
没什么，当美洲杯到来时，我说，是的，那是正确的时间。
And nothing, when the Copa América arrived I said, yes, that is the right time.
Y nada, cuando llegó la Copa América dije, sí, ese es el momento indicado.
无论结果如何，无论结果如何，我认为正如我已经说过的
whatever it ends, whatever this turns out, I think that as I have already said
termine como termine, salga como salga esto, creo que como ya lo he dicho
我可以平静地走进那扇门，平静地走进那扇大门。
I can go through the door calmly, the big door calmly.
Me puedo ir por la puerta tranquilo, la puerta grande tranquilamente.
我付出了一切，我没有更多可给予，我知道那些......
I gave everything, I have no more to give and I knew that those...
Lo di todo, ya no tengo más para dar y sabía que esos...
有六场比赛，七场美洲杯比赛，那是……
There were six games, seven Copa América games, that was...
Seis partidos que había, siete partidos de la Copa América, era lo...
最后一件事我打算把一切都留在那
the last thing and I was going to leave everything at that
lo último y iba a dejar todo en eso que
在喝完最后一杯酒后，我知道我已经完成了。
in that last drink and then from there I knew I was done.
en esa última copa y después a partir de ahí sabía que ya estaba.
也许在卡塔尔之后没有离开可以强化这样一种观念：美洲杯是最后一件事，让我们从正在发生的事情中走出来。
Perhaps not having left post-Qatar served to reinforce that the Copa América was the last thing, to move on from what was happening.
quizás no haber dejado post-Catar te sirvió para reforzar que la Copa América era lo último, pasar a lo que pasaba.
通过了。
passed.
pasara.
是的，是的，因为正如我告诉过你的，世界杯结束后我并没有……
Yes, yes, because, as I told you, after the World Cup I wasn't...
Sí, sí, porque, como te dije, después del Mundial no estaba...
这不是 100%，而是 70% 说我停下来，我不会停下来，我停下来，我不会停下来。
It's not 100%, it was 70% of saying I stop, I don't stop, I stop, I don't stop.
No es un 100%, estaba un 70% de decir dejo, no dejo, dejo, no dejo.
我不太确定，但是世界杯结束时
I wasn't completely sure, but when the World Cup ended
No estaba seguro del todo, pero cuando terminó el Mundial
季后赛即将回归，一切，嗯，就像......
and the playoffs were coming back and everything, well, it's like...
y ya venían eliminatorias de vuelta y todo, bueno, es como que...
我说，就是这样，这就是美洲杯。
I said, that's it, it's the Copa América.
Dije, ya está, es la Copa América.
最后一场预选赛是在马拉卡纳对阵巴西队。
Just the last qualifying match was against Brazil in Maracaná.
Justo el último partido eliminatoria era contra Brasil en Maracaná.
这是赢了，巴西从未输过，我认为这就像......
it was won, Brazil had never lost and I think it was like...
se ganó, Brasil no había perdido nunca y creo que era como...
查塔，是时候了。
Chata, it was time.
Chata, era el momento.
完美结束阶段，什么也没有，我想我已经赢得了我所赢得的
Perfect to close stages and nothing, I think having won what I won
Perfecto para ir cerrando etapas y nada, creo que haber ganado lo que gané
最终在预选赛中赢得巴西新兴市场冠军。
end up winning EM Brazil in the qualifying cup.
terminar ganando el EM Brasil en la copa eliminatoria.
巴西从未输过球，然后进入了美洲杯......
that Brazil had never lost and then reached the Copa América...
que nunca había perdido Brasil y después llegar a la Copa América...
完美，因为国家队正处于一个伟大的时刻，这是正确的时间。
perfect because the national team was in a great moment, it was the right time.
perfectos porque la selección estaba en un gran momento, era el momento indicado.
你是如何面对美洲杯的？
And how did you face the Copa América?
¿Y cómo afrontaste la Copa América?
这不是第一场小组赛比赛，但是……
Not the first group stage matches, but...
Ya no los primeros partidos de fase de grupo, sino...
我们越来越近了，我们将与厄瓜多尔进行点球大战，然后与加拿大的科尼科队进行点球大战，然后……
We are getting closer, there is a penalty shootout with Ecuador, then the Cónico in Canada, and there...
nos vamos acercando, hay una definición por penales con Ecuador, después la Cénico en Canadá, y ahí...
这可能已经是你的最后一场比赛了，也就是说，很明显阿根廷队将在小组赛中晋级。
It could already be your last game, that is, it was quite clear that Argentina was going to pass in the group stage.
Ya podía ser tu último partido, o sea, estaba bastante claro que Argentina en la fase de grupos la iba a pasar.
但从四分之一决赛开始，如果你输了，你就出局了。
But starting in the quarterfinals, if you lose you go.
Pero ya a partir de cuartos, si perdés marchás.
它改变了你一点点。
It changed you a little.
Te cambiaba un poco.
是的，我改变了，在对阵厄瓜多尔的比赛中我吃了不少苦头。
Yes, I changed and I suffered a lot in the game against Ecuador.
Sí, me cambiaba y el partido contra Ecuador lo sufrí mucho.
首先是因为我没有进去，我知道如果我们被留在外面......
First because I hadn't gone in and I knew that if we were left outside...
Primero porque no había entrado y sabía que si quedábamos afuera...
是要这样退休，但是当
was to retire that way, but when
era retirarme de esa manera, pero cuando
我们去了监狱等等，我说在经历了这一切之后我不能再这样生活了。
We went to the prisons and everything, I said I can't live this way after everything I had suffered.
Nos fuimos a los penales y todo, yo decía no me puedo vivir de esta manera después de todo lo que había sufrido.
所有美好的事物来了，就这样又离开了，就像最后一半崩溃了一样。
and all the good things that came, leaving again like that, like half crashing there at the end.
y toda la buena que vino, irme otra vez así, como medio chocando ahí al final.
我坚信我们会通过，而且最终......
I had that faith that we would pass, and well, in the end...
Tenía esa fe de que pasábamos, y bueno, al final...
我们最终通过了，但什么也没发生，就是那种我们即将进入决赛的感觉
We ended up passing and nothing, it was that feeling that we were reaching the final
terminamos pasando y nada, era esa sensación de que a la final llegábamos
我一直有这种感觉，它一直都在那里。
I always had that feeling, it was always there.
Esa sensación siempre la tuve, siempre estaba ahí.
潜伏着事情会是那样的。
latent that it was going to be that way.
latente de que iba a ser de esa manera.
决赛后能否获胜取决于很多因素。
Winning it or not after the final depends on many factors.
Ganarlo o no después de la final depende de muchos factores.
上面的那个是最后一个跟随所有内容的，所以......
and the one above is the last one that ends up following everything, so...
y el de arriba es el último que termina siguiendo todo, entonces...
我不知道这一点，但我确实知道我们有一支选拔团队可以进入决赛并且能够......
I didn't know this, but I did know that we had a selection team to reach the final and be able to...
Esto no lo sabía, pero sí sabía que teníamos equipo selección para poder llegar a la final y poder...
不和厄瓜多尔比赛的感受如何？
And how did you experience not playing against Ecuador?
¿Y cómo viviste eso de no jugar contra Ecuador?
你和莱昂内尔·斯卡罗尼谈过这件事吗？
Did you talk about it with Lionel Scaloni?
¿Lo hablaste con Lionel Scaloni?
因为斯卡罗尼什么都知道。
Because Scaloni knew everything.
Porque Scaloni sabía todo.
你不仅要战胜厄瓜多尔，而且这可能是你的最后一场比赛。
Not only did you have to get past Ecuador, but that could be your last game.
No solo que había que pasar Ecuador, sino que ese podía ser tu último partido.
是的，是的，我赛后谈到了这件事。
Yes, yes, I talked about it after the game.
Sí, sí, lo hablé después del partido.
我认为之后有训练的图像，我认为厄瓜多尔随后参加了比赛......
I think there are images of a training session afterwards, I think Ecuador played afterwards...
Creo que hay imágenes de un entrenamiento después, creo que después Ecuador tocó...
加拿大，对吗？
Canada, right?
Canadá, ¿no?
是的，整个加拿大，感动了加拿大。
Yes, all of Canada, which touched Canada.
Sí, todo Canadá, que tocaba Canadá.
他来告诉我他要参加比赛，
who came to tell me that he was going to play,
que me vino a decir que iba a jugar,
他要再次比赛，我知道什么，他告诉我，如果我们被排除在外而我不参加比赛，他想杀了我，我知道什么。
that he was going to play again, what do I know, and he told me, he wanted to kill me if we were left out and I didn't play, what do I know.
que iba a volver a jugar, qué sé yo, y me dijo, me quería matar si llegamos a quedar afuera y no jugaba, qué sé yo.
我在那里告诉他，你就是个王八蛋，怎么能不放下我呢？
And there I told him, you're a son of a bitch, how can you not put me down?
Y ahí le dije, sos un hijo de puta, ¿cómo no me vas a poner?
如果我们能留在外面不打最后一场比赛就好了。
If we could stay out and not play the last game.
Si podíamos quedarnos fuera y no jugar el último partido.
他告诉我他杀了我，每个人都用我不知道什么杀了我，但是嘿，总是这样
and he tells me he killed me, everyone killed me with I don't know what but hey, always with that
y me dice me mataba yo me mataban todos de no sé qué pero bueno siempre con eso
带着他作为教练的幽默感，他决定，这些都是时刻，人们也能理解。
With that humor that he is the coach, he decides, these are moments and one also understands it.
Con ese humor de que es el entrenador, decide, son momentos y uno también lo entiende.
显然他很热，他可以妓女。
Obviously he gets hot, he can whore.
Obvio que se calienta, que puede putear.
这很正常，没有人有竞争力，总是想在那里，想参加比赛。
It's normal, no one is competitive and always wants to be there, wants to play.
Es lo normal, no uno es competitivo y quiere estar siempre, quiere jugar.
更重要的是，当他知道这是最后一件事，我们被排除在外时，他不再参加比赛了。
And even more so when he knows that it is the last thing, that we were left out, he didn't play anymore.
y más cuando sabe que es lo último, que quedábamos afuera, no jugaba más.
我脑子里有这一切，但后来我和他聊天，一切都很好，一如既往。
I had all that in my head, but then I chatted with him and everything was more than fine, as always.
Tenía todo eso en la cabeza, pero después charlé con él y todo más que bien, como siempre.
问题是他们已经有了，他在这个空间里告诉了这一点，当你……时的谈话。
The thing is that they had already had, and he told this in this space, that talk when you...
Es que ya habían tenido, y esto lo contó él en este espacio, esa charla cuando vos...
你在巴黎写了一张纸条，说我更愿意将自己置于 4500 万阿根廷人之中。
You give the note in Paris and say I prefer that I put myself in 45 million Argentines.
das la nota en París y decís prefiero que me pute en 45 millones de argentinos.
在埃菲尔铁塔附近的酒吧喝咖啡之前，他给你打电话。
before having a coffee in a bar near the Eiffel Tower, and he calls you on the phone.
antes de tomar un café en un bar cercano a la Torre Eiffel, y él te llama al toque.
他说，即使在该系列中，也有一个专门的空间来讨论这个话题，他讲述了这个话题，最后他们都听起来了。
Even in the series there is a space dedicated to that talk and he tells it and they both end up sounding, he says.
incluso en la serie hay un espacio dedicado a esa charla y él lo cuenta y terminan sonando los dos dice él
是的，他就是这么说的，我想我已经说过好几次了。
Yes, that's how he told it and I think I've already told it several times.
Sí, es como lo contó él y creo que yo ya lo conté varias veces.
因为他发出的便条结束了该便条，而且他已经在那里了
in that the note he was giving ended the note and he already had there
en que en esa nota que estaba dando terminó la nota y ya tenía ahí
里奥·斯卡洛尼（Leo Scaloni）打电话给我，但没有任何反应，我接了他，我们开始聊天，但没有任何反应，这就是为什么
Leo Scaloni was calling me and nothing, I answered him, we started chatting and nothing, that's why
Leo Scaloni que me estaba llamando y nada, lo atendí, empezamos a charlar y nada, por eso
回到我告诉过你的话，我想现在是时候停止了
Going back on what I was telling you, I think now is the time to stop
Volviendo para atrás en lo que te contaba, creo que ahora es el momento de dejar
是时候离开了，因为我认为即将到来的孩子们已经接受过训练，他们已经......
It was time to leave because I think that the kids who are coming are already trained, they already have...
fue el momento de dejar porque creo que los chicos que ya vienen ya están formados, ya tienen...
一个基地，一个也去了......
a base and one went too...
una base y uno le fue también...
伴随着这一切，像尼科，像
accompanying in all that, like Nico, like
acompañando en todo eso, como Nico, como
就像巴纳乔一样，就像所有即将到来的人一样。
like Barnacho, like all those who were coming.
como Barnacho, como todos los que estuvieron viniendo.
晚安。
Good night.
Buenas noches.
所以最后有人留下了一些东西并展示了如何
So in the end one left things and showed how
Entonces al final uno fue dejando cosas y fue mostrando como
你对这件球衣的感觉如何，你如何试图向你身后的男孩们展示。
how you feel the shirt, how you try to show the boys who are behind you.
cómo uno siente la camiseta, cómo intenta demostrarle a los chicos que vienen detrás.
当时就是这样，离开那里是正确的，这样所有这些男孩才能继续下去。
At the time it was this, it was the right one to leave there so that all these boys could continue for it.
en el momento era este, era el indicado para dejar ahí para que todos estos chicos sigan por él
沿着这条路走下去，我认为当我开始的时候，我没有付出任何代价，我开始玩，然后我去了银行
down this path and I don't think it cost me anything when I started, I started playing, then I went to the bank
por este camino y nada creo que a mí me costó cuando arranqué que empecé jugando después fui al banco
我的位置上有一些球员。
There were players in my biggest position.
había jugadores de mi posición más grande.
这让我有点受伤，因为是时候更新了，但它没有发生。
and it kind of hurt me a little because it was time for renewal, it wasn't happening.
y como que un poco me dolió porque era momento de renovación, no pasaba.
我想我不喜欢这种事发生在我身上，所以...
and I think I didn't like it happening to me, so...
y creo que no me gustó que me pase, entonces...
我希望当我离开时，我觉得这是男孩们的时间，我认为是时候了。
I wanted that when I leave, I feel that it was the boys' time and I think it is the time.
Quería que cuando yo me vaya, sienta que era el momento de los chicos y creo que es el momento.
我36岁了。
I am 36.
Yo tengo 36.
继续留在那里就像施加压力
continuing to be there is like putting pressure
seguir estando ahí es como meter presión
玩时，对游戏是否开始或我是否进入或是或是施加压力。
to play, put pressure on whether the game starts or if I enter or yes or yes.
para jugar, meter presión de si juego arranque o si entro o si o si.
并把这个空间从他们身上夺走，不，事实是我不会允许这样做。
and take that space away from them and no, the truth is that I wouldn't allow it.
y sacarle ese espacio a ellos y no, la verdad que no me lo permitiría.
您有看到与您感觉相似的足球运动员吗？
Do you see any footballer that you feel similar to?
¿Ves algún futbolista que vos sientas parecido?
给你，如果你愿意的话，从一开始，在第一场比赛中。
to you, if you want, at the beginning, in those first games.
a vos, si querés, en el comienzo, en esos primeros partidos.
2007年U-20世界杯，奥运会，可可的召唤。
U-20 World Cup in 2007, Olympic, Coco's call.
Mundial Sub-20 en 2007, olímpico, la convocatoria de Coco.
很难将自己与某人或......进行比较
And it's hard to compare yourself to someone or...
Y es difícil compararse con alguien o...
从这一面来看，我们都是非常不同的。
Looking from that side, we are all very different.
Mirar desde ese lado, todos somos muy diferentes.
这很困难，我认为这里有很多素质很高的球员。
It's difficult, I think there are players with a lot of quality.
Es difícil, creo que hay jugadores con muchísima calidad.
我真的很喜欢 Guaranote，它的品质令人难以置信。
I really like Guaranote, it has incredible quality.
A mí me gusta mucho Guaranote, tiene una calidad increíble.
俱乐部已经证明了这一点，而国家队的好处就是一点一点地试图展现自己
and the clubs show it and the good thing in the national team is little by little trying to show itself
y lo demuestran los clubes y bueno en la selección poco a poco va intentando mostrarse
有时候进国家队很难，不容易。
It is sometimes difficult to get into the national team, it is not easy.
Cuesta a veces entrar en la selección, no es fácil.
正如我常说的，有成千上万的阿根廷球员。
As I always said, there are thousands and thousands of Argentine players.
Como dije siempre, son miles y miles de jugadores argentinos.
最终只有 25、26、27 个人去那里，而且去那里也很困难。
and there are only 25, 26, 27 that end up going there and it is difficult to be there too.
y solamente hay 25, 26, 27 que terminan yendo ahí y es difícil después estar ahí también.
但他是我真正喜欢的球员之一。
But he is one of the players that I really like.
pero es uno de los jugadores que a mí me gusta muchísimo.
这不是......同样的事情总是发生，这不是因为他来自中后卫或其他什么，但他是一名球员......
It's not... The same thing always happens and it's not because he came from center back or anything, but he is a player that...
No es... Siempre pasa lo mismo y no es porque haya salido ni de central ni nada, pero es un jugador que me...
我喜欢他的品质、他的踢球方式以及他对足球的感受，我认为这也是
I like him for his quality, for how he plays, for how he also feels about football and I think that also
Me gusta por su calidad, por cómo juega, por cómo siente también el fútbol y creo que también
他是一名今后可以为国家队做出很多贡献的球员。
He is a player who can give a lot to the national team from now on.
Es un jugador que le puede dar mucho de acá en adelante a la selección.
我回到了2024年美洲杯，决赛的剧本很精彩，比赛因为quilombo而推迟了......
I return to the Copa América 2024, the final has a tremendous script, the match is postponed due to a quilombo...
Vuelvo a la Copa América 2024, la final tiene un guión tremendo, el partido se posterga por quilombo...
在体育场礼仪中。
in the stadium decencies.
en las adecencias del estadio.
你和家人有什么问题吗？
Did you have any problems with the family?
¿Vos tuviste algún problema con la familia?
你有留意吗？
Were you paying attention?
¿Estuviste atento?
起初是的，但后来我的家人就像一个
at first at first yes but then my family just came in like a
al principio al principio sí pero después justo mi familia entró como un
我先于其他人快速敲击，因为我已经和一群人在一起了
I tapped quickly before the others because I was with a group already
toque rápido antes que la demás porque estaba con un grupo ya de
的家庭都在一起并且能够进入，但我确实知道有......
of families all together and were able to enter, but I do know that there was...
de familias todos juntos y pudieron entrar, pero sí sé que había...
许多球员的家人也不在场。
much of those of the players' family who were away as well.
mucho de las de la familia de los jugadores que estaba fuera también.
尽管如此，他们还是不让他进来，还让他走哪条路，他们度过了一段糟糕的时光。
Still, they didn't let him in and they made him go one way or the other and they had a bad time.
todavía, que no dejaban entrar y que lo hacían ir por un lado o por el otro y la pasaron mal.
在哥伦比亚党内，科纳里亚、詹姆斯和理查德·里奥斯在右翼掌权
and in the party Colombia rules with Conaria, James and Richard Ríos on the right
y en el partido manda Colombia con Conaria, James y Richard Ríos en la derecha
在那场比赛中，斯卡罗尼进行了一次交换和调整。
And there is a swap, an adjustment for Scaloni in that match.
Y hay un trueque, un ajuste de Scaloni en ese partido.
是的，我从一侧开始，最终在另一侧玩耍。
Yes, I started on one side and ended up playing on the other.
Sí, arranqué por un lado y terminé jugando por el otro.
但是，嘿，这就是足球。
but hey, that's football.
pero bueno, es el fútbol así.
他们也是为此而存在的，教练和助理们在比赛期间都会关注所有这些事情。
They are there for that too, the coach is there to look at all those things during the game, the assistants.
Ellos están para eso también, el entrenador está para mirar todas esas cosas durante el partido, los ayudantes.
并做出这些微小的改变......
and make those small changes in...
y hacer esos pequeños cambios en...
在比赛的某些时刻，它可以给你很多东西，事实是，这是一个惊人的变化，因为我们开始了
in moments of the game where it can give you a lot and the truth is that it was a spectacular change because we started
en momentos del partido en donde te puede dar muchísimo y la verdad que fue un cambio espectacular porque empezamos
为了获得更多得分机会，我们创造更多得分情况
to have many more scoring chances, we create many more scoring situations
a tener muchas más ocasiones de gol, creamos muchas más situaciones de
从球场中间向前推进，一开始对我们来说很困难，但效果很好。
from the middle of the court forward which was difficult for us at the beginning and it was very good.
de mitad de la cancha para adelante que nos estaba costando al principio y estuvo muy bien.
你是怎么发现的，因为你在另一边？
How did you find out, because you were on the other side?
¿Cómo te enteraste vos, porque estabas del otro lado?
不，他打电话给我，他开始对我大喊大叫，让我换到另一边，然后……
No, he called me, he started yelling at me to change to the other side and...
No, me llamó, me empezó a gritar para que cambie para el otro lado y...
我什么都不注意，我只想在他们告诉我的地方打球，我从一侧到另一侧都打得一模一样。
and I don't pay attention to anything, I only want to play where they tell me, I play from one side to the other exactly the same.
y nada yo hago caso yo quiero jugar solamente donde me digan yo juego de un lado del otro exactamente igual
后来我总是尽力而为却一事无成
Afterwards I always try to do my best but nothing
después intento siempre hacer lo mejor posible pero nada
他叫我改变地点，什么也不做，继续前进。
He called me to change the location and nothing, to move forward.
Me llamó para que cambie el lugar y nada, a seguir para adelante.
在游戏中，狮子座崩溃了。
And in the game Leo breaks down.
Y en el partido se rompe Leo.
摄像机跟着他，在体育场的屏幕上你可以看到里奥的哭泣比比赛还要多。
and the cameras follow him and on the stadium screens you can see Leo's crying more than the game.
y las cámaras lo siguen y por las pantallas del estadio se ve más el llanto de Leo que el partido.
那个时候你能跟他聊什么？
What were you able to talk to him about at that time?
¿Qué pudiste hablar con él en ese momento?
不，他第一次击球时扭伤了脚踝
No, the first time he hit it, he twisted his ankle
No, en la primera vez que se golpeaba, que se doble el tobillo
我问他那里，他告诉我他自己弯了腰，但是很疼。
I asked him there and he told me that he had doubled over on his own but that it hurt a lot.
Le pregunté ahí y me dijo que se había doblado solo pero que le dolía un montón.
然后，如果我，你看，你想要的只是让我在球场上阅读，那么一切都不那么重要了。
And then, if I, you see, all you want is for me to read on the field, then everything doesn't matter exactly the same.
Y como que después, si yo, viste, vos lo único que querés es que leo dentro de la cancha, después da todo exactamente igual.
然后随着他的继续，一切都结束了。
Then as he continued, everything was over.
Entonces como él siguió, como que todo se terminó.
接下来的打法是他又双倍了，我也去了。
The next play was that he doubled again, and I went there too.
La jugada siguiente fue que se vuelve a doblar otra vez, que yo también me acerco ahí.
我已经看到了...
and I already saw that...
y ya lo vi que ya...
我半哭半笑，皱着眉头，然后我意识到……
I was half crying and frowning and then I realized that...
estaba medio como llorando y que hacía ceña y ahí me di cuenta de que...
他受伤了，就在那时灯开始熄灭，因为
that he had been injured and that's when the lights start to go out because
de que se había lesionado y ahí es cuando se empiezan a apagar las luces porque
我们必须开始审视我们在做什么、去哪里、以什么方式。
We have to start seeing what we do, where we go, in what way.
Hay que empezar a ver qué hacemos, para dónde salimos, de qué manera.
我们扭转了不让孩子上场的情况。
We reversed not having the baby on the field.
revertimos el no tener al nena dentro de la cancha.
在那里你说了些什么，或者你知道，因为你非常了解他，没有什么比这更好的了。
and there you say something or you know, because you know him very well, that nothing is better.
y ahí se le dice algo o sabés, porque lo conoces muy bien, que mejor nada.
不，不，首先什么也没说，因为他受伤了，而且因为……
No, no, nothing is said first because he has an injury and because...
No, no, no se dice nada primero porque tiene una lesión y porque...
他问出来，你就已经意识到他不可能继续下去了。
For him to ask out, you already realize that it is impossible for him to continue.
Para que él pida salir, ya te das cuenta de que es imposible que pueda seguir.
这是一件很严重的事情，你不会对他说什么。
that it's something serious and there's nothing you're going to say to him.
de que es algo grave y nada qué le vas a decir.
你只能看着他，什么也别说，你不能对他说什么。
You look at him and nothing else, you can't say anything to him.
Lo mirás y nada más, no puedes decirle nada.
这是一个...的时刻
It is a moment of...
Es un momento de...
由于发烧，由于紧张，由于一切，有时最好保持沉默。
from fever, from nerves, from everything, that sometimes it is better to be silent.
de calentura, de nervios, de todo, que es mejor a veces estar callado.
这是你的最后一场比赛，也是美洲杯决赛，他们进入加时赛，
It's your last game and it's a Copa América final, they go to extra time,
es tu último partido y es una final de Copa América, van a la prórroga,
你是如何度过这种二元性的？
How did you live that duality?
¿Cómo vivías esa dualidad?
因为对于每个人来说，这都是美洲杯的决赛。
Because for everyone it was the final of the Copa América.
Porque para todos era la final de la Copa América.
但对你来说，另外，这是你的最后一场比赛，也就是说，除了记录下来之外，你的队友没有人知道，
But for you, in addition, it was your last game, that is, something that none of your teammates, beyond the fact that they recorded it,
Pero para vos, además, era tu último partido, o sea, cosa que ninguno de tus compañeros, más allá de que registraban eso,
你能感受到你的感受吗？
Could you feel how you felt?
¿Podías sentir como sentías vos?
事实是，这种感觉是...
The truth is that the feeling was...
La verdad que la sensación era...
有点奇怪，因为……
a little strange, because...
un poco extraña, porque...
有时我觉得我是最后一个，一切都真的结束了。
At times I felt like I was the last and that everything was really over.
Por momentos sentía que era el último y que se terminaba todo de verdad.
太感谢了！
Thank you so much!
¡Muchas gracias!
但有时候，那件事就像是从我的脑海中消失了，而我只是在参加决赛。
but at times it was like that thing was going out of my head and I was just playing in the final.
pero por momentos era como que se me iba eso de la cabeza y era solo jugar la final.
就好像有时我知道这是最后一件事，有时又不知道。
It was like at times I knew it was the last thing and at times I didn't.
Era como por momentos que sabía que era lo último y por momentos no.
这是一种感觉，事实是，很难解释。
It was a sensation, the truth is, that is difficult to explain.
Era una sensación, la verdad, que es difícil de explicarla.
这很奇怪。
It was very strange.
Fue muy extraño.
我在上一场比赛中经历了什么以及我女儿们的加入。
what I experienced that last game with also the entry of my daughters.
lo que viví ese último partido con también la entrada de mis hijas.
有了球，一切的感觉就这么说吧
with the ball those sensations of everything let's say that
con la pelota esas sensaciones de todo digamos de que
一切都在同一个游戏中同时发生，但是......
Everything was happening together in the same game, but...
Estaba pasando todo junto en un mismo partido, pero...
但什么也没有发生，就像安心一样，无论发生什么，就这样，什么也没有发生。
But nothing, as with a peace of mind that whatever happens, that's it, nothing happened.
Pero nada, como con una tranquilidad de que pase lo que pase, ya está, no pasaba nada.
很明显他想赢，他想以最好的方式结束比赛。
It's obvious that he wanted to win, that he wanted to finish in the best way.
Es obvio que quería ganar, que quería terminar de la mejor manera.
但另一方面，我相信我已经付出了一切，我已经实现了我想要的，那就是
but on the other hand I was confident that I had given everything and that I had achieved what I wanted, which was
pero por otro lado estaba con la tranquilidad de que lo había dado todo y de que había logrado lo que quería que era
再次闯入新的决赛，让阿根廷再次登顶。
to reach a new final again and put Argentina at the top again.
volver a llegar a una nueva final y volver a poner otra vez a Argentina en lo más alto.
你对进球的体验如何？
How do you experience the goal play?
¿Cómo vivís la jugada del gol?
进球的表现令人难以置信。
The goal play was incredible.
La jugada de gol fue increíble.
首先是因为
First because
Primero porque
这背后也有一些东西。
There is something behind it too.
Hay algo detrás también.
没人知道那是在世界杯决赛中。
that was never known, that it was in the World Cup final.
que nunca se supo, que fue en la final del Mundial.
当 Leo 带我出去时，他告诉我他一会儿会给我打电话，并告诉我......
When Leo takes me out, he tells me that he will call me in a moment and tells me that...
Cuando me saca Leo, él me dice que me llama en un momento y me dice que...
大约还有五分钟，类似的事情，他离开了，因为我想科多曼要进来了。
about five more minutes, something like that, and he was leaving because Kodoman was going to enter, I think.
que unos cinco minutos más, algo así, y que salía porque iba a entrar Kodoman, creo.
他们会大量攻击他，他会派人进去加强一点，然后……
and that they were going to attack him a lot and that he was going to put someone in there to reinforce a little and well, then...
y que le iban a atacar mucho y que iba a meter a alguien ahí para reforzar un poco y bueno, entonces...
那一刻我告诉他好吧。
I told him okay at that moment.
Yo le dije bueno en ese momento.
没有考虑接下来会发生什么，或者我打得怎么样，或者事情进展如何。
without thinking about what could happen next or how I was playing or how things were going.
sin pensar en qué podía pasar después o cómo estaba jugando yo o cómo iban las cosas.
而在本届美洲杯上，当加时赛上半场结束时
And in this Copa América, when the first half of extra time ends
Y en esta Copa América, cuando termina el primer tiempo de la prórroga
我撒了第二个或第一个或第二个我不太记得了我认为这是第一个
I lie the second or the first or the second I don't remember well I think it was the first
miento el segundo o el primero o el segundo no me acuerdo bien creo que fue el primero
不，我在撒谎，第二个，他说完就给我打电话，告诉我……
No, I'm lying, the second one, he calls me when he finishes talking and tells me...
No, miento, el segundo, él me llama cuando termina de hablar y me dice...
几分钟后他就会带你出去，因为他看到我浑身局促，再也受不了了。
a few minutes and he'll take you out because he saw that I was all cramped and couldn't take it anymore.
unos minutos y te saco porque vio que yo estaba todo acalambrado y que no podía más.
那一刻我告诉他不，不要带我出去，不要带我出去。
And at that moment I told him no, don't take me out, don't take me out.
Y en ese instante yo le dije no, no me saques, no me saques.
我不知道为什么，但那一刻我发现它没有带我出去，也没有带我出去。
I don't know why but it came out at that moment that it didn't take me out and it didn't take me out.
no se porque pero me salio en ese momento de que no me saque y no me saco
我们最终进球了，而我最终却空了，比方说
and we ended up scoring the goal and I ended up leaving empty let's say
y terminamos haciendo el gol y me termine yendo vacionado digamos
就像我之前告诉过你的那样，在同一个游戏中发生的一切都是不可能的......
It's like what I was telling you before, everything happened to me in the same game that is impossible to...
Es como que lo que te decía antes, me pasó todo en un mismo partido que es imposible de...
能够展示所有这些感觉，但一切都发生在我身上。
to be able to demonstrate all those sensations, but everything happened to me.
de poder demostrar todas esas sensaciones, pero me pasó todo.
一切都很完美，没有什么不好的，什么都没有，零。
Everything was perfect, there was nothing bad, nothing, zero.
Todo perfecto, no hubo nada malo, nada, cero.
一切都很顺利。
Everything went perfectly.
Todo salió a la perfección.
曾是...
Was...
Fue...
事情必须如此，上面的人希望事情是这样的，结果就这样发生了
as it had to be, the one above wanted it to be that way and it happened that way
como tenía que ser, el de arriba quería sea de esa manera y se dio así
最重要的是，进球后，你必须在那里放第五名后卫，尼科进来，然后你出来，但比赛已经是一比零了。
And on top of that, after the goal, you have to put a fifth defender there, Nico comes in and then you come out, but the game was already one to zero.
Y encima después del gol, ahí hay que poner un quinto defensor, entra Nico y ahí sí salís vos, pero ya el partido estaba uno a cero.
太感谢了！
Thank you so much!
¡Muchas gracias!
当然，当然，准确。
Sure, sure, exact.
Claro, claro, exacto.
我认为这比他之前想做的更有可能，否则我不知道他要派谁。
I think that was possible than what he wanted to do before or I don't know who he was going to put.
Yo creo que eso era capaz que lo que quiso hacer antes o no sé a quién iba a poner.
但没什么，我不想出去，因为我想赢得比赛
but nothing, I didn't want to go out because I wanted to win the game
pero nada, no quería salir porque yo quería ganar el partido
他还有一个特点，那就是他总是在决赛中进球，并且在那里取得了一些进球。
And he also had that thing that he had always scored goals in the finals and had had some there.
Y tenía eso también de que siempre había hecho goles en las finales y había tenido algunas ahí.
清楚，他们无法进入，而且什么都没有
clear and that they had not been able to enter and nothing was with that
claras y que no habían podido entrar y nada estaba con eso de que
我可以在某个时刻进球。
I could score a goal at some point.
la podía meter a un gol en algún momento.
但什么也没有，最后我进了劳塔罗，我最终离开了，什么也没有。
and nothing and in the end I scored Lautaro, I ended up leaving, nothing.
y nada y al final hice el gol Lautaro, terminé saliendo, nada.
一切都很完美。
Everything perfect.
Todo perfecto.
2022年世界杯决赛中，
In the 2022 World Cup final,
En la final del Mundial de 2022,
你告诉他，我进了第三个，你带我出去，他说，不，我现在不会带你出去，因为法国拥有一切，这是真的吗？
Is it true that you tell him, I make the third and you take me out and he says, no, I won't take you out now because France comes with everything?
¿Es verdad que vos le decís, hago el tercero y me sacás y él dice, no, no te saco ahora porque Francia viene con todo?
或者是城市伤害。
or it is an urban injury.
o es una lesión urbana.
不，那一刻……
No, that's the moment when...
No, ese es el momento en el que...
我告诉他他告诉我他要花我大约五分钟，类似的事情。
in which I tell him that he told me that he was going to take me about five minutes, something like that.
en el que le digo que él me dice que me iba a sacar unos cinco minutos, algo así.
因为他告诉我科曼将进入，他们将全力以赴向前推进
and because he told me that Coman was going to enter and that they were going to put everything in to move forward
y porque me dijo que iba a entrar Coman y que ellos iban a meter todo para ir para adelante
他想加强一点，就在那时我告诉他好吧。
and he wanted to reinforce there a little and that's when I told him okay.
y que quería reforzar ahí un poco y fue cuando yo le dije que bueno.
但告诉他他进球后就离开了，不，不是那样。
but telling him that he scored the goal and left, no, not that.
pero decirle que hacía el gol y salía, no, eso no.
他很漂亮，别带我出去。
He's beautiful, don't take me out.
Hermoso él, no me saqués.
我的意思是，它来自你的灵魂，仿佛在说，好吧，这是我的最后一场比赛，不要带我出去。
I mean, it came from your soul as if to say, well, it's my last game, don't take me out.
O sea, te salió del alma como diciendo, bueno, es mi último partido, no me saqués.
是的，但是当我告诉他...
Yes, but when I told him...
Sí, pero cuando se lo dije...
因为当他告诉我他要离开的时候，关于世界杯的一切都浮现在我的脑海里，然后就出来了……
It was because when he told me he was leaving, everything about the World Cup came to mind and it came out...
Fue porque cuando él me dijo que salía, se me vino todo a la cabeza lo del mundial y me salió...
只是不，别带我出去，因为没有什么像我知道的那样
just no, don't take me out because nothing was like I know that
solo el no no me saques porque nada era como sé que
事情必须如此，正如我告诉过你的，我必须留下来直到我们进球，然后离开。
It had to be that way, as I told you, I had to stay until we scored the goal and then leave.
tenía que ser de esa manera como te digo tenía que quedarme que hagamos el gol y después salir
我是如何以我想要的方式出来、鼓掌的。
how I came out, applauded and in the way I wanted.
como salí, ovacionado y de la manera que deseaba.
在你的职业生涯中非常优秀和非常有影响力的教练现在我们要谈论一些但是
very good and very influential coaches in your career now we are going to talk about some but
entrenadores muy buenos y muy influyentes en tu carrera ahora vamos a hablar de algunos pero
这一步放在哪里，即使在消极的时刻，我也记得 2019 年美洲杯，
where does that step put it and even in negative moments, I remember the 2019 Copa América,
en qué lugar lo pone esa escalón y hasta incluso por momentos negativos, yo me acuerdo de la copa América 2019,
你是第一场比赛的先发球员，然后你甚至进入了一个时刻
that you are a starter in the first game and then you even enter a moment where
que sos titular en el primer partido y después hasta incluso entras en un momento donde
可以说，你的公众形象相当低。
Your public image was pretty low, so to speak.
tu imagen pública estaba bastante abajo, por decirlo de alguna forma.
虚无，虚无。
The nada, the nada.
La ñada, la ñada.
假设之后他们之间建立了一种令人难以置信的联系，在你的便条之后聊天。
and let's say that afterwards they end up having an incredible bond, the chat after your note.
y digamos que después terminan teniendo un vínculo increíble, la charla después de tu nota.
说到你希望或宁愿被 4500 万阿根廷人骂的是什么。
Speaking of what you wanted or preferred to be bitched by 45 million Argentines.
Hablando de que querías o preferías que te putearan 45 millones de argentinos.
美洲杯决赛的对话。
the dialogue of the final, this one from the Copa América.
el diálogo de la final, este de Copa América.
你还记得第一次见到他是什么时候吗？
Do you remember when you first met him?
¿Te acordás cuando lo conociste a escalón?
让我们谈谈你和他的关系。
And let's talk a little about your relationship with him.
Y hablemos un poquito de tu relación con él.
嗯，当他和圣保利一起来的时候我就认识了他。
Well, I met him when he came with San Paoli.
Bueno, lo conocí cuando vino con San Paoli.
当然。
Of course.
Claro.
在那里我开始与他建立那种关系，在那里我开始明白那是什么
There I began to have that relationship with him and there I began to see what it was
ahí empecé a tener esa relación con él y ahí empecé a ver que era
他是一个好人，一个正面、直接的人。
that he was a good person, that he was a frontal, direct person.
que era una buena persona, que era una persona frontal, directa.
他喜欢做爱，他喜欢总是开玩笑，什么都喜欢，又什么都不喜欢。
that he liked to fuck, that he liked to always be joking, everything, and nothing.
que le gustaba joder, que le gustaba estar siempre bromeando, todo, y nada.
我从一开始就非常喜欢他...
I liked him very well from the first...
Me cayó muy bien desde el primer...
从第一天开始。
From the first day.
Desde el primer día.
但好吧，然后美洲杯的事情发生了。
But well, then the Copa América thing happened.
Pero bueno, después pasó lo de la Copa América.
很好，正如你所说，我...
That's good, as you said, I had...
Que bueno, como dijiste tenía...
图像有点受损，但是有很多人利用了这一点
the image was a little damaged and well there were many people who took advantage of that
la imagen un poco dañada y bueno había mucha gente que se aprovechaba de eso
他们开始编造我和他打架的事，因为他在第一场对阵哥伦比亚的比赛中场休息时把我淘汰了。
and they began to invent that I got into a fight with him, because he took me out at halftime against Colombia in the first game.
y empezaron a inventar que me peleé con él, que porque me sacó en el entretiempo contra Colombia en el primer partido.
然后我俩就吵架了，吵架了，不知道怎么回事……
Then I had a fight, we argued, I don't know what...
Después me peleé, que discutimos, de que no sé qué...
一千件事，一如既往，已经稍微损害了形象，
a thousand things that, as always, having already damaged the image a little,
mil cosas que, como siempre, al tener un poco ya dañada la imagen,
继续携带东西更容易。
It's easier to keep carrying things.
Es más fácil seguir cargando con cosas.
一个人把它存入银行，仅此而已，他就让它过去了。
One banked it and that's it, he let it pass.
Uno la bancó y ya está, lo dejó pasar.
但以那样的方式或其他方式战斗的人
but one who fights like that in that way or whatever
pero uno que se pelea así de esa manera o lo que sea
如果教练当时说得容易多了，我就不会再提了。
If the coach, at that moment, had had it much easier to say, I won't mention it more.
Si el entrenador, en ese momento, él lo hubiese tenido muchísimo más fácil de decir, no lo cito más.
其他人不会谈论他或说什么。
Nobody else is going to talk about him or say anything.
Nadie más va a hablar de él ni va a decir nada.
如果在某个时候我们...对他来说很容易
It was very easy for him if at some point we had...
Era muy fácil para él si en algún momento tuvimos...
就像大家说的那样，一场战斗，但不，不是那样的，他把我带走了，一切都很好
a fight like everyone said but no, it wasn't like that, he took me out, everything was fine
una pelea como todo el mundo decía pero no, no fue así, él me sacó, estaba todo bien
我继续训练，我不得不去银行
I kept training, I had to go to the bank
seguí entrenando, me tocó ir al banco
因为我总是要去，然后好吧，当他打电话给我的时候，他打电话给我，他告诉我
as I always had to go and then well, when he called me that time he called me he told me
como me tocó ir siempre y después bueno, él cuando me llamó esa vez que me llamó me dijo
我上次已经告诉过你了，你...
I already told you the other time, you are...
ya te lo dije la otra vez, sos...
对于许多孩子来说非常沉重，当你在这里时，孩子们会承受很大的压力，因为他们知道会发生什么。
very heavy for many of the kids, the kids have a lot of pressure when you are here because they know what is going to happen.
muy pesado para para muchos de los chicos tienen mucha presión los chicos cuando estás acá porque saben qué va a pasar
你可以玩，你可以参加，我不知道是什么。
You can play, you can enter for it, I don't know what.
puedes jugar, que podés entrar por ello, no sé qué.
好吧，我说是的，我知道，但是......
And well, I said yes, I know, but...
Y bueno, yo le dije sí, ya sé, pero...
比赛、年复一年、几个月过去了，我想在那里，我不想不在那里。
The games, the years, the months go by and I want to be there, I don't want to not be there.
Se me van pasando los partidos, los años, los meses y yo quiero estar, no quiero no estar.
我告诉他，我不希望孩子们打得不好或者孩子们打得不好都是我的错……
I tell him, I don't want it to be my fault that the boys play badly or that the boys don't...
Le digo, tampoco quiero que sea culpa mía de que los chicos jueguen mal o que los chicos no...
不，不要放弃，因为我在银行，无论如何，Ligo，但我想成为，Ligo，请原谅我，但是......
No, don't give up because I'm on the bank, whatever, Ligo, but I want to be, Ligo, forgive me, but...
No, no rindas porque yo estoy en el banco, lo que sea, Ligo, pero yo quiero estar, Ligo, perdoname, pero...
这是我想要的，也是我一直觉得的，在国家队是最好的，在俱乐部我做得很好
It is what I want and what I always felt, being in the national team is the best, at the club I am doing things well
es lo que deseo y lo que siempre sentí, estar en la selección es lo máximo, en el club estoy haciendo las cosas bien
我认为我应该在那里，他告诉我，你怎么能不值得，我不知道是什么？
And I think I deserve to be there and he tells me, how can you not deserve I don't know what?
Y creo que merezco estar ahí y me dice, ¿cómo no vas a merecer no sé qué?
他告诉我，保持冷静，我不知道什么，好吧，从下一场开始我就回来了，感谢上帝。
He tells me, stay calm, I don't know what, well, and from the next one I was back, thank God.
Me dice, quédate tranquilo, no sé qué, bueno, y a partir de la siguiente volví a estar, gracias a Dios.
甚至他在我们为这个空间做的笔记中也谈到了它的重要性。
Even he, in the note we made for this space, talked about how important it was too.
Incluso él en la nota que hicimos para este espacio habló de lo importante que era también
尼科·冈萨雷斯（Nico González）也是如此，他当时是卢卡斯·奥坎波斯（Lucas Ocampos）。
also for Nico González, who at that time was Lucas Ocampos.
también para Nico González, que en ese momento estaba Lucas Ocampos.
没有安赫尔·迪玛丽亚作为替补。
not having Ángel Di María as a substitute.
no tener a Ángel Di María de suplente.
我们将进入两场决赛。
We are going to two finals.
Vamos a dos finales.
首先我想从最接近的开始，2024年之后就是2022年。
First I want to start with the closest one, after 2024, it is 2022.
Primero quiero empezar por la más cercana, después de la de 2024, es la de 2022.
你是什​​么时候发现自己要打11号位的？
When did you find out that you were going to play as an 11?
¿Cuándo te enterás de que vas a jugar de 11?
在与法国队的比赛之前，埃斯卡洛尼是如何向你解释的？
And how does Escaloni explain it to you before the game with France?
¿Y cómo te lo explica Escaloni antes del partido con Francia?
不，我是在开会的时候在去现场之前看到的。
No, I saw it at the time of the meeting before going to the field.
No, lo vi en el momento de la reunión ante ir a la cancha.
直到那天直到我们进入房间的那一刻，他
until the day until that minute we entered the room and he
hasta el día hasta ese minuto de que entramos a la sala y él
它在图像中放入了 11，我什么都不知道。
It puts 11 in the image, I didn't know anything.
pone el 11 en la imagen, no sabía nada.
0 0 0 因为前一天我们训练了 5
0 0 0 because the day before we had trained with 5
0 0 0 porque el día anterior habíamos entrenado con 5
我们已经创造了死球
we have made dead balls with with with
hayamos hecho pelotas paradas con con con
三个中后卫什么的，我什么都没参加，我是替补
the three center backs and everything and I had not participated in anything, I was a substitute
los tres centrales y todo y yo no había participado en nada estaba como suplente
那里什么也没有，当我们去演讲的那一刻我发现了
and nothing was there and well I found out at that moment when when we go to the talk
y nada estaba ahí y bueno me enteré en ese momento cuando cuando vamos a la charla
当我看到我没有看到自己在右边时，我说就这样了，但当然，当我看到我身后只有四个人时
When I see and I don't see myself on the right I said that's it but of course when I see that there were only four behind me
cuando veo y no me veo en la derecha dije ya está pero claro cuando veo que había cuatro atrás nomás solamente
我向左看去，发现就在左边。
I looked to the left and found that it was on the left.
Miré para la izquierda y me encontré que estaba a la izquierda.
首先，我什么都不明白，因为除此之外我...
First of all, I wasn't understanding anything because on top of that I had...
Primero que no estaba entendiendo nada porque encima tenía...
总是坐在墙边，并且在什么时候都保持干净
always sits next to the wall and clear when
siempre se sienta lea pared al lado y claro cuando
你可以看到我在左边，我看着他，他用眼角的余光看着我，就像……
You can see there that I'm on the left side, I look at him and he looks at me out of the corner of his eye like...
Se ve ahí el que estoy del lado izquierdo, lo miro y me mira de reojo como...
你看起来很奇怪，因为他不知道为什么，之后他开始解释为什么他开始
You looked strange because he didn't know why and nothing after that he started to explain why he started to
raro viste porque no no sabía por qué y nada después empezó a explicar por qué empezó a
告诉我们他对比赛的看法以及在这方面他可以......
to tell us what he thought of the game and that on that side he could...
a decirnos que era lo que él pensaba del partido y que por ese lado podía...
我可以有所作为，我可以享受乐趣，因为我不是...
I could make a difference, I could have fun because I wasn't a...
podía hacer la diferencia, que me podía divertir porque no era un...
他不是边锋，他是中后卫，他们在之前的比赛中已经见过他，他们很清楚他就是这样的。
He wasn't a winger, he was a center back and they had already seen him in the previous games and they were very clear that he was that way.
no era un lateral, era un central y que ya lo habían visto en los partidos anteriores y que lo tenían muy claro que era por ahí.
然后事情必须解决，他们必须为我解决，这也很难让一切发生，但是哦，好吧
then things have to work out and they had to work out for me, it was also difficult for everything to happen but oh well
después las cosas tienen que salir y a mí me tenían que salir era era difícil también que pase todo pero bueno
结束了，结束了
it's over it's over
se terminó se terminó dando
当你看到记分表时，是在球场上，已经在卢塞尔体育场了吗？
Is that on the field, already in the Lusail stadium, when you see the scoresheet?
¿Eso es en la cancha, ya en el estadio de Lusail, cuando ven la planilla?
不，在酒店。
No, at the hotel.
No, en el hotel.
但在比赛当天。
But on game day.
Pero el día del partido.
作为？
As?
¿Cómo?
比赛当天还是比赛前一天？
The day of the game or the day before?
¿El día del partido o el día anterior?
不不不，比赛那天……
No, no, the day of the game...
No, no, el día del partido...
距离上车去外地还有五分钟。
five minutes before getting on the bus to go to the field.
cinco minutos antes de subir al colectivo para ir para la cancha.
直到那一刻我才知道我要上场比赛。
I didn't know anything until that moment that I was going to play.
No supe nada hasta ese momento de que iba a jugar.
当然，我的意思是，这是三个中后卫，我想利桑德罗......
Of course, I mean, it was three center backs, I imagine that with Lissandro...
Claro, o sea, era tres centrales, me imagino que con Lissandro...
每个人都认为我们正在与三名中后卫一起比赛。
Everyone thought we were playing with three centre-backs.
Todos pensaron que jugábamos con tres centrales.
所有的男孩，因为我们就是这样训练的，因为当我们停止球时，球就停止了
all the boys because we train it that way and because the ball stops when we do the ball stop
todos los chicos porque lo entrenamos así y porque la pelota parada cuando hacemos la pelota parada
球已经停止了，因为它已经
The ball is already stopped because it is already
ya está la pelota parada porque ya está
计划好每个人将如何得分，我们将如何穿着它，仅此而已。
planned how each one is going to score, how we are going to wear it and that's it.
planeado cómo va a marcar cada uno, cómo nos vamos a poner y listo.
但是，嘿，很明显，以后，随着你拥有的球员，如果你改变系统或方式......
But hey, it's obvious that later, with the players you have, if you change the system or the way...
Pero bueno, es obvio que después, con los jugadores que tenés, si cambiás el sistema o cambiás la forma...
你立即解决他们，他们是两个聪明的球员，能够
You settle them right away and they are two intelligent players to be able to
los acomodas enseguida y son dos jugadores inteligentes para poder
组织得又快又好
organize quickly but well
organizarse rápido igual pero bueno
我想象你的脸，我不在右边，但你意识到，不，但我在另一边，也就是说，我要去玩。
I imagine your face, I'm not on the right, but you realize, no, but I'm on the other side, that is, I'm going to play.
Me imagino tu cara, en la derecha no estoy, pero vos te das cuenta, no, pero estoy del otro lado, o sea, voy a jugar.
的框架内
within the framework of
en el marco de
我说，在我向左转的那一刻，我就要去玩的感觉
The feeling that I was going to play the moment I turned left I said
La sensación de que iba a jugar en el momento en que me di por izquierda dije
我首先说为什么要离开？
First I said why left?
Primero dije ¿por qué por izquierda?
然后我说我已经报仇了。
and then I said I have my revenge.
y después dije tengo mi revancha.
2014 年的那张，所以它包含了所有内容，而且很好
the one from 2014 so it kind of had all that in it and well
la del 2014 entonces como que como que tenía todo eso dentro y bueno
巴伊亚已经开始紧张，这也很好。
The nerves have already started in Bahia, which is also good there.
en bahía empezaron ya los nervios que también bueno ahí
在我的系列中，在我的纪录片系列中，帕布力托……
In my series, in my documentary series that I did, well, Pablito...
En mi serie, en mi documental serie que hice, bueno, Pablito...
他很好地解释了我的双腿开始颤抖，移动它们。
He explains it very well that I start to tremble with my legs, to move them.
Lo explica muy bien que empiezo a temblar con las piernas, a moverlas.
我从小就有的腿和东西。
the legs and things of mine that I have had since I was little.
las piernas y cosas mías que tengo desde chiquito.
在那场比赛中，我认为前两场比赛进展顺利，你获得了信心。
And in that match I think the first two went very well and you gained confidence.
Y en ese partido creo que las dos primeras te salen muy bien y tomás confianza.
是的，我是那种第一次表现不好并不意味着我会失败的球员。
Yes, I am one of those players that if I don't do well the first time it doesn't mean that I fall.
Si, soy de esos jugadores que si no me sale bien la primera no es que me caigo.
我不认为他们会成功，但我是那些即使没有第一个，事情也会进展顺利的人之一。
I don't think they're going to work out, but I'm one of those people who, without the first one, things turned out well.
que pienso que no me van a salir pero soy si de esos de que ya sin la primera me salieron las cosas bien
然后一切都出来了，就像...
Then everything comes out, it's like...
después me sale todo, es como que...
这获得了信心，我知道如果没有第一个......
that gained that confidence and I know that without the first one...
que agarró esa confianza y sé que ya sin la primera ya...
我接受了，我已经知道下一篇稍后会是......
I took it, I already know that later in the next one it will be...
Me lo llevé, ya sé que después en la siguiente va a estar...
带着恐惧，我将能够按照自己的意愿前进，好吧，我就是这样的人之一。
with fear and that I will be able to move forward as I want and well, I am one of those like that.
con miedo y que voy a poder ir para adelante como quiero y bueno, soy de esos así.
库德就是这样。
And that happened with Cudé.
Y pasó eso con Cundé.
事情确实发生了，从我抓住的第一个开始，我开始面对它，我觉得
It happened exactly, from the first one I grabbed, I started to face it, I felt
pasó exactamente ya desde la primera que agarré ya empecé a encarar me sentí
她害怕，而在那一边她也……
that she was afraid and on that side she was also...
que ella estaba con miedo y encima de ese lado también estaba...
还有登贝莱，他也不是后卫，他是一个纯粹的推销员。
There was Dembélé, who is not a defender either, he is a pure salesman.
estaba Dembélé, que tampoco es un defensor, es vendantero puro.
好吧，最后事情进展得很顺利，好吧，它最终让我......
And well, in the end things end up going really well, well, it ends up making me...
Y bueno, al final la cosa se termina andando re bien, bueno, de medias termina haciéndome...
点球什么也没有，我认为这是一场精彩的比赛。
the penalty and nothing, I think it was a spectacular game.
el penal y nada, creo que fue un partido espectacular.
这是犯罪吗？
Was it criminal?
¿Fue penal?
是的，这是犯罪行为。
Yes, it was criminal.
Sí, fue penal.
没人相信我，疯了。
Nobody believes me, crazy.
No me cree nadie, loco.
这是一个非常明确的处罚。
It was a very clear penalty.
Fue penal clarísimo.
一个高速移动的人只要轻轻一碰就能稳定你，事情就是这样。
A person at high speed with a single touch stabilizes you and that's what happened.
Una persona a mucha velocidad con un solo toquecito te estabiliza y fue lo que pasó.
那是一种触动，让我感动，让我跌倒。
It was a touch that touched me and made me fall.
Fue un roce que me tocó y me hizo caer.
在进球的过程中，你的表现如何？
And in the play of the goal, how have you been beating?
¿Y en la jugada del gol cómo venís palpitando vos?
来自朱利安的压力，来自斯卡罗尼的姿态。
That pressure from Julián comes, that gesture from Scaloni.
Viene esa presión de Julián, ese gesto de Scaloni.
你在这场比赛的对面，它来自对面。
You are on the opposite side with the play, it comes from the opposite side.
Vos estás por el lado opuesto con la jugada, viene por el lado opuesto.
法国队在左侧进攻，阿根廷队在右侧防守，
in France's attack on the left side, right side of the Argentine defense,
en el ataque de Francia a costado izquierdo, lado derecho de la defensa argentina,
你是否因“嘿，也许轮到我了”而感到悸动？
And how are you throbbing with “hey, maybe it's my turn”?
¿Y cómo vas palpitando de «hey, quizás me toca»?
你什么时候意识到“这对我来说将会结束”？
When do you realize that "and this is going to end for me"?
¿Cuándo te das cuenta de que «y esta va a terminar para mí»?
不，呃……当我意识到一切都会有好结果的那一刻……
No, uh... The moment I realize that it's going to end well is when...
No, eh... En el momento que me doy cuenta que va a terminar bien es cuando...
当朱利安把它交给亚历克西斯时当亚历克西斯
when just when julian gives it to alexis when alexis
cuando recién cuando a julian se la da alexis cuando alexis
他开始深入，朱利安把球传给了他
He starts to run deep and Julian gives it to him
empieza a correr en profundidad y Julian se la da
就在那时我觉得比赛在我这边结束了。
That's when I felt the play was ending on my side.
Es cuando sentí que terminaba la jugada de mi lado.
在我开始陪戏之前
Before I started to accompany the play
antes arranqué a acompañar la jugada por
因为这也是利奥也要求我做的事情之一
because well it was one of the things that Leo had also asked me to be
porque bueno fue una de las cosas que también Leo nos había me había pedido que era
让它下降，但不要下降到让我摆脱困境的程度，因为我们在哪里偷东西
let it go down but not so much that it left me a touch off the hook because where we were stealing
que baje pero no tanto que me quede un toque descolgado porque en la que robábamos
我们可以和我一起快速出击，进行一些反击，进行快速的深传。
We could go out quickly with me, with some counterattacks, with a quick deep pass.
Podíamos salir rápido conmigo, con alguna contra, con un pase rápido en profundidad.
好吧，当他看到我们偷东西的时候。
And well, when he saw that we stole.
Y bueno, cuando ya vio que robamos.
而球到了矮子那里，你就知道有一个99.9的人不丢球。
And the ball reaches the dwarf, you know that there is a 99.9 who does not lose it.
Y la pelota le llega al enano, ya sabés que ahí es un 99.9 que no la pierde.
比赛将继续进行，当朱利安已经将球传给亚历克西斯时，什么也没有发生
that the game will continue and nothing when Julián already makes the pass to Alexis is when
que la juega va a seguir y nada cuando Julián ya mete el pase a Alexis es cuando
当我到达那里时，我感觉球最终会来到我身边。
When there I feel that the ball is going to end up coming to me.
Cuando ahí siento que la pelota va a terminar llegándome a mí.
您什么时候选择这样定义？为什么？
And when do you choose to define this way and why?
¿Y cuándo elegís definir así y por qué?
定义毫秒，因为它们是人们思考和反应的毫秒
define that millisecond because they are milliseconds in which one thinks and reacts
definir esa milésima de segundo porque son milésima de segundo en la que uno piensa y reacciona
但背后总有人会问一些事情。
But there are things behind that one always asks.
Pero hay cosas detrás que uno siempre pregunta.
实践、观察、研究以及……
that practices, that sees, that studies and well...
que practica, que ve, que estudia y bueno...
守门员教练赛前告诉我
The goalkeeper coach had told me before the game that
el entrenador de arquero me había dicho antes del partido que
他们的脚很快就伸出来了，他们很快就扑倒了。
that their feet came out very quickly, that they threw themselves very quickly.
que salían muy rápido los pies, que se tiraban muy rápido.
当我们玩游戏时，我们可以有一些计数器。
As we were playing the game we could have some counters.
Como estábamos playendo el partido de que podíamos tener algunas contras.
好吧，他告诉我的关于我的事情比我关于捡起它、举起它的事情还要多。
Well, he told me more about mine than I am about picking it up, lifting it up.
bueno, él me lo decía más por la mía que yo soy de picarla, de levantarla
查门总是告诉我一些事情，他告诉我他是一个跳跃的弓箭手
The chamen always tells me something and he had told me that he was an archer who jumped
El chamen siempre me tira alguna data y él me había dicho que era un arquero que se tiraba
离脚非常低，反应迅速，并且始终保持伸展状态
very low to the feet, quick to react down and always remained stretched out
mucho abajo a los pies rápido a reaccionar abajo y se quedaba siempre todo estirado
好吧，当球来到我身边时，我会尝试用力击球，使球越过顶部。
And well, when the ball comes to me I try to overhit it so that the ball goes over the top.
y bueno cuando me llega la pelota intento pelarle de sobrepique para que la pelota salga por arriba
因为很难击中它或者其他原因，因为防守者非常接近，所以......
because it was very difficult to hit it or something because the defender was very close so it was...
porque era muy difícil picarla o algo porque tenía el defensor muy cerca entonces era...
尝试快速完成比赛，但尝试举起球，这是唯一的方法。
Try to finish quickly but try to lift the ball and it was the only way.
Intentar definir rápido pero intentar levantar la pelota y era la única manera.
你在马德里的队友奥西尔有这样的击球方式吗？
Did your teammate in Madrid Ócil have that way of hitting the ball?
¿Tu compañero en el Madrid ócil tenía esa forma de pegar la pelota?
是的，是的，我有过。
Yes, yes I had.
Sí, sí tenía.
他有那种真正的方式。
He had that real way.
tenía esa manera real.
还有2021年的目标
And also the goal in 2021
Y también el gol en 2021
它背后有一段历史，因为...
It has a history behind it, because...
tiene una historia atrás, porque...
他们谈到了雷南、洛迪的干扰，还有……
They have talked about the distractions of Renan, Lodi and also...
han hablado de las distracciones de Renan, Lodi y además...
他的位置接近于一个纯粹的左撇子，这已经需要他用右手比用左手更多地干预。
his positioning to close being such a pure left-hander on a ball that already requires him to intervene more with his right than with his left.
su posicionamiento para cerrar siendo un zurdo tan puro en una pelota que ya le demanda más intervenir con la derecha que con la zurda.
是的，这就是我告诉你的，有时它们是小信息。
Yes, that's what I'm telling you, sometimes they are small pieces of information.
Sí, es lo que te digo, a veces son pequeñas informaciones.
最终对你有帮助的小事情以及更多。
little things that help you in the end and more in.
pequeñas cosas que te ayudan al final y más en.
在这样的决定性比赛中，在对方球队的比赛中，对方选择。
in such decisive matches, in matches where the other team, the other selection.
en partidos tan decisivos, en partidos donde el otro equipo, la otra selección.
11人通常都是9分或10分，他们都是顶级球员。
The 11 are normally 9 or 10 points, they are top players.
Los 11 normalmente son de 9 o 10 puntos, son jugadores top.
是的，或者如果你必须尝试寻找他们可能存在的弱点，那么，在那一刻......
Yes or if you have to try to look for that weakness that they may have and well, at that moment it was...
si o si tenés que intentar buscar esa debilidad que puedan llegar a tener y bueno, en ese momento fue...
小天使曾告诉我他的后背深处很心不在焉
little angel who had told me that he was very distracted in the depths of his back
angelito que me había dicho que se distraía mucho en la profundidad en la espalda
安杰利托·科雷亚 是的，让他尝试找回自己，我不知道会发生什么，那么好吧
Angelito Correa yes, let him try to find his back and I don't know what and well then
Angelito Correa sí, que intente buscarle la espalda y no sé qué y bueno entonces
就在那一刻，我告诉罗德里，安杰利托告诉了我这一点。
At that moment I told Rodri that Angelito had told me that.
En ese momento le dije a Rodri que Angelito me había dicho eso.
我告诉他，你在田野中央找到的那个
and I tell him, you in the one that you find it there in the middle of the field
y le digo, vos en la que la encuentres ahí por la mitad de la cancha
你已经知道我要逃跑，那么无论他是否给我，都不会发生任何事情，我要去太空。
You already know that I'm going to run, then whether he gives it to me or not, nothing happens, I'm going to space.
Vos ya sabés que yo voy a correr, después si me la da o no, no pasa nada, yo voy al espacio.
最后，在太空中的平均奔跑也有点......
that in the end, the average run in space is also a bit...
que al final, la corrida media en espacio también es un poco...
为矮人提供了开放空间，他们可以在两线之间接收。
open space for the dwarf who can receive there between the lines.
abrirle espacio al enano que pueda recibir ahí entre líneas.
没有压力，因为我会做出无论你走到一边还是走到中间的动作
without pressure because I am going to make the movement of whether you go to the side and to the center always
sin presión porque voy a hacer el movimiento de si vas al lateral y al central siempre
因为？
Because?
¿Por qué?
因为边锋必须很奇怪，而且因为中后卫......
Because the winger has to be strange and because the center back...
Porque el lateral tiene que ser raro y porque el central...
他总是处于防守状态，生怕你从他身后吃掉他的背。
He is always on the defensive that you could eat his back from behind him.
siempre está la defensiva de que te puedas comer la espalda por detrás de él.
所以我总是尝试做出这些动作，以便中间的人能够接收到。
So they are movements that I always try to make so that those in the middle can receive.
Entonces son movimientos que yo siempre intento hacer para que los del medio puedan recibir.
所以我告诉他，如果你扔它，你就扔它，好吧，我会去。
So I told him, if you throw it, you throw it and well, I'll go.
Entonces yo le dije, vos si la tirás, la tirás y bueno, yo voy.
好吧，当他第一次接住球时，他就把球投了进去，传球非常完美。
And well, the first time he grabbed it he put it in and the pass went perfect.
y bueno en la primera que agarró la metió y el pase salió perfecto
洛迪之前只是稍微碰了一下它，然后让我更好地进行控制。
Lodi just touches it a little bit before and leaves it even better for me to be able to do the control.
Lodi justo la toca un poquitito antes y me la deja mejor todavía para poder hacer el control.
好吧，当我有控制权时，把它扔到顶部对我来说是完美的。
And well, when I had control, it was perfect for me to throw it over the top.
Y bueno, cuando ya me quedó el control, me había quedado perfecta para tirarla por arriba.
守门员贾斯图斯已经向前移动了一点，并在后面获得了空间。
The goalkeeper Justus had already moved forward a little and had that space back there.
El arquero Justus ya había salido un poco para adelante y tenía ese espacio ahí atrás.
这种从上面定义这么多记录的能力从何而来？
Where does this ability to define from above with so many records come from?
¿De dónde viene esa capacidad para definir por arriba con tantos registros?
戳它，戳它，用脚背打它……
poke it, poke it, hit it with your instep...
pincharla, picarla, darle con el empeine...
它不仅是一种将其扔到顶部的方法，而且还有多种定义模式。
Not only is it the method of throwing it over the top, but you have several definition patterns.
no sólo es la modalidad de tirarla por arriba, sino que tenés varios patrones de definición.
是的，我不知道，我觉得这对我来说...
Yeah, I don't know, I feel like it's like for me...
Sí, no sé, siento que es como para mí...
最简单的定义方法，我不知道为什么，我觉得这样做比......更安全
The easiest way to define, I don't know why, I feel safer doing that than...
La manera más fácil de definir, no sé por qué, me siento más seguro haciendo eso que...
试图一对一地打开脚并将其从侧面或珍珠扔出去......
that trying one on one to open the foot and throw it from the side or pearle of...
que intentando en uno contra uno abrir el pie y tirarla por un costado o pearle de...
三个手指，就像是……那一刻，就像是……
three fingers, it's like it's a... at that moment it's like the...
de tres dedos, es como que es un... en ese momento es como que la...
那一刻我的感觉是，我更容易放下脚步了。
What I feel at that moment is that it is much easier for me to put my foot down.
Lo que siento en ese momento es que mucho más fácil para mí es meter el pie abajo.
球并举起来，这对我来说是最容易的，我不知道为什么。
of the ball and lifting it, it's what comes easiest to me, I don't know why.
de la pelota y levantarla, es lo que me sale más fácil, no sé por qué.
瑞士队的进球就是倾斜身体并将内侧边缘射入球门。
The goal with Switzerland has that thing about tilting the body and putting the inside edge into it.
El gol con Suiza tiene eso de inclinar el cuerpo y meterle el borde interno.
是的，但是那里距离更远，弓箭手是……
Yes, but well there it was further away, the archer was...
Sí, pero bueno ahí estaba más lejos, el arquero estaba...
越靠近弧线，就越难以定义，否则它是我唯一剩下的一个
more on the line of the arc it is more difficult to define otherwise it is the only one that remained for me
más sobre la línea del arco es más difícil de definir de otra manera es la única que me quedaba
在那一刻也控制飞行员
also control the pilot at that moment
controlar también la pilota en ese momento
这给了球队到达的机会，所以当他来的时候，就让他
It gives the side the chance to arrive so as it came it was to put him
le da la posibilidad al lateral llegar entonces como venía era meterle
到另一个门柱并尝试走到守门员身边接球。
to the other post and try to catch it by walking to the goalkeeper.
al otro palo y intentar agarrarlo caminando al arquero.
对于另一边。
for the other side.
para el otro lado.
它们是人们多年来看到并学到的东西。
They are things that one sees over the years and learns as well.
Son cosas que uno va viendo durante los años y va aprendiendo también.
你喜欢足球吗？你热衷于战术、策略吗？
Do you like football, are you passionate about tactics, strategy?
¿Te gusta el fútbol, te apasiona de táctica, de estrategia?
我们也在谈论技术，如何击球，如何尝试在 3 号位和 6 号位之间潜行。
We're talking about technique too, about how to hit the ball, how to try to sneak between the 3 and the 6.
Estamos hablando de técnica también, de cómo pegar la pelota, cómo tratar de colarse entre el 3 y el 6.
你总是喜欢足球或时间流逝，并且你发现对分析更感兴趣。
You always liked football or time passed and you found more interest in what analysis is.
siempre te gustó el fútbol o pasó el tiempo y le fuiste encontrando más interés a lo que es el análisis.
随着时间的流逝，我越来越喜欢这最后一次......
As time went by I liked it more and more this last time from the...
Cuando fue pasando el tiempo me fue gustando más y más este último tiempo a partir de los...
30岁以后我开始对一切都感兴趣了
From the age of 30 I began to be much more interested in everything
de los 30 empezó a interesarme mucho más todo
看看更多。
to look much more.
de mirar mucho más.
现在，当我观看比赛时，我会更加集中注意力。
Now when I watch the games I pay much more attention.
Ahora cuando miro los partidos preto mucho más atención.
我尝试分析一下空间在哪里、在哪里
I try to analyze a little about where the spaces are, where
intento analizar un poco por donde están los espacios, por donde
他们留下了空隙。
They leave the gaps.
Dejan los huecos.
我不知道，这是我最后一次
I don't know, this last time is the one in which I
No sé, este último tiempo es en el que más me
我进入了这个角色，事实是我真的很喜欢它。
I got into that role and the truth is that I really like it.
Me metí en ese rol y la verdad es que me gusta mucho.
学习越来越多，我不知道，玛丽安娜节也是如此，对吗？
learn more and more and well, I don't know, for Mariana's Day too, right?
ir aprendiendo cada vez más y bueno, no sé, para el Día de Mariana también, ¿no?
你永远、永远不知道，但是...
You never, never know, but...
Nunca, nunca sabe, pero...
但是，嘿，事实是我越来越喜欢它。
But hey, the truth is that I liked it more and more.
Pero bueno, la verdad que cada vez me fue gustando más.
当你在电视上观看比赛时是一回事，当你在玩比赛时又是另一回事。
One thing is when you watch the game on television and another is when you are playing it.
Una cosa es cuando uno ve el partido por televisión y otra es cuando lo está jugando.
我向利奥询问了他假装参加的那些散步的情况……
I asked Leo about those walks he pretends to be on...
A Leo le pregunté por esas caminatas en las que él finge estar...
忽略了比赛，但实际上他关注的是可能发生什么以及他可以在哪里造成伤害。
neglecting the game, but in reality what he is looking at is what can happen and where he can do damage.
desatendiendo el juego, pero en realidad lo que está mirando es qué puede pasar y por dónde puede hacer daño.
当游戏不适合你时，你会在什么地方停下来？
What do you stop at in moments where perhaps the game is not for you?
¿Vos en qué te detienes en momentos donde quizás el juego no pasa por vos?
但也许两三分钟后我可以去接你。
but maybe I can pick you up two or three minutes later.
pero quizás sí pueda pasar por vos dos o tres minutos después.
是的，正如我一直说的那样，我是那些
Yes, as I always said and always say, I am one of those who
Sí, como siempre dije y lo digo siempre, soy de esos que
谢谢大家！
Thank you all!
¡Gracias a todos!
谁去太空，谁喜欢去太空，谁总是关注太空。
who goes to space, who likes to go to space, who is always attentive to that.
que va al espacio, que le gusta ir al espacio, que está siempre atento a eso.
然后也是那些喜欢参加的人之一，我是那些参加比赛的球员之一
and then also one of those who likes to attend, I am one of those players who
y después también de esos de que le gusta asistir, soy de esos jugadores que
我真的很喜欢参加，当我参加时我感觉自己进球了。
I really like attending, I feel like I score the goal when I attend.
que me gusta mucho asistir, siento que hago el gol yo cuando asisto.
如果我进球了，我会觉得是我独自完成的，而且
If I score the goal I feel that I am doing it alone and that
si hago el gol yo siento que lo estoy haciendo yo solo y que
不是我的搭档，但当我参加时，我觉得我也在这样做，而且满足感对我来说是双倍的。
Not my partner, but when I attend I feel like I'm doing it too and the satisfaction is double for me.
que no mi compañero pero cuando asisto siento que yo también lo estoy haciendo y es doble para mi la satisfacción.
所以我真的很喜欢助攻并找到能够得分的空间。
So I really like to assist and find those spaces to be able to score the ball.
Entonces me gusta mucho asistir y encontrar esos espacios para poder meter la pelota.
但没什么，当我们从下面打球时，当球在另一边时，
But nothing, when we came out playing from below, when the ball was on the other side,
Pero nada, cuando salimos jugando de abajo, cuando la pelota estaba por el otro lado,
我总是在寻找它可以去哪里......
I'm always seeing where it can go...
Estoy siempre viendo por dónde puede llegar a...
跟随比赛能够加速或能够去...
to follow the play to be able to accelerate or to be able to go to...
a seguir la jugada para poder acelerar o para poder ir a...
寻找我脚下的球并能够协助而不是让他们协助我。
to look for the ball at my foot and be able to assist and not have them assist me.
a buscar la pelota al pie y poder yo asistir y no que me asistan a mí.
但是，嘿，它们是比赛的时刻，有时只是几秒钟。
But hey, they are moments of the game that sometimes are seconds.
Pero bueno, son momentos de partido que a veces son segundos.
轮子从一侧开始，前几天我们对阵波尔图，当时我进球了。
that the wheel starts on one side, the other day we played against Porto, when I scored the goal.
que la rueda arranca por un lado, el otro día que jugamos contra Porto, que hice el gol.
如果你从远处看到这个图像......
If you see the image from afar...
Si se ve la imagen de lejos...
我已经看到了，因为事后我喜欢看我是如何进球的，我是如何做出动作的。
that I already saw it, because afterwards I like to look at how I scored the goal, how I made the movement.
que yo ya la vi, porque después me gusta mirar cómo hice el gol, cómo hice el movimiento.
我们几乎没抢到球
We barely stole the ball
Apenas robamos la pelota
谁偷了它，他们想从侧面按压并偷它
who steals it, they want, on the side, to press and steal it
que la roba quieren, en el costado, que presione y la roba
当他勉强偷球时，我已经开始向前推进，因为我知道对方已经落后了。
When he barely stole, I had already started to go forward knowing that the side already had him behind.
cuando apenas roba yo ya había empezado a ir para adelante sabiendo que el lateral ya lo tenía atrás
因为已经可以继续前进了
because it was already open to go forward
porque ya estaba abierto para ir para adelante
而且我还有剩余空间，所以我之前就已经开始了。
and that I had space left, so I had already started before.
y que me quedaba el espacio, entonces yo ya había arrancado desde antes.
知道如果球从中间传给弗雷德和我们的中场球员
knowing that if the ball came in the middle to Fred and our midfielder
sabiendo de que si la pelota venía para el medio a Fred y al mediocampista nuestro
我本来打算自己买通行证，所以我以前见过它，但正如我告诉你的那样，它们是
I was going to have the pass for myself so I had seen it before but as I told you they are
iba a tener el pase para mí entonces ya lo había visto antes pero como te digo son
人们认为可以过去的几秒钟，有时也很好......
Seconds that one thinks can pass and well sometimes...
Segundos que uno piensa que puede pasar y bueno a veces...
它当然会发生，但是，例如，有一天它最终发生了。
It happens of course, but well, for example, the other day it ended up happening.
Pasa como no, pero bueno, por ejemplo, el otro día terminó pasando.
是啊，呃...
Yeah, uh...
Sí, eh...
是穆里尼奥开始让你采取不同的腿、倒立的轮廓吗？
Is it Mourinho who starts to put you on a different leg, inverted profile?
¿Es Mourinho el que te empieza a poner a pierna cambiada, perfil invertido?
踢中路，本菲卡踢中路到左路。
having played centrally and Benfica more from the middle to the left.
habiendo jugado en central y Benfica más desde el medio hacia la izquierda.
是的，我一直踢左边路，从我很小的时候一直到我2010-2011年来到马德里。
Yes, I always played on the left, always from when I was little until I arrived in Madrid in 2010-2011.
Sí, siempre jugué por izquierda, siempre desde chiquitito hasta que llegué a Madrid 2010-2011.
那是当...
It was when...
fue cuando...
当克里斯蒂亚诺在另一边时，我不得不为自己腾出空间，最后......
when Cristiano was on the other side and I had to make room for myself and well, in the end...
cuando estaba Cristiano del otro lado y tenía que hacerme un hueco y bueno, al final...
我最终走到了右边
I ended up going to the right side and well
terminé yendo al lado derecho y bueno
我开始喜欢那里，我开始在那个位置感到非常舒服，从那里开始
I started to like it there, I started to feel very comfortable in that position and from there
me empezó a gustar ahí, empecé a sentirme muy cómodo en esa posición y a partir de ahí
最终我的整个职业生涯几乎都打在右路。
In the end I also played almost my entire career on the right.
al final también jugando casi toda mi carrera por derecha.
他是怎么说服你的？
How did he convince you?
¿Cómo te convenció?
除此之外，你看，克里斯蒂亚诺在左边，所以你不会在那里踢球，但一定有一些争论也会吸引你。
Beyond, look, Cristiano is on the left so you're not going to play there, but there have to be arguments that also seduce you.
Más allá de, mira, en la izquierda está Cristiano así que ahí no vas a jugar, pero tiene que haber argumentos que también te seducen.
没有……他什么都不用告诉我，他不可能往左边走。
There was no... He didn't have to tell me anything, it was impossible for him to go to the left.
No había... No tenía que decirme nada, era imposible que fuera por izquierda.
在4-3-3阵型中，他不可能打左边路
Playing 4-3-3 it was impossible for him to play on the left
jugando 4-3-3 era imposible que juegue por izquierda
没什么，我必须适应接下来发生的事情，我已经知道了
and nothing, I had to adapt to what came next, I already knew that
y nada, me tenía que adaptar a lo que había después, ya sabía que
卡里姆和皮帕的战绩是 2 胜 9 负，好吧……
that Karim and Pippa were 2-9 and well...
que Karim y el Pippa eran los 2-9 y bueno...
是的，是的，它是在右边踢的，但事实是……
It was playing on the right, yes or yes, but the truth is...
Era jugar por derecha sí o sí, pero la verdad que...
我适应得很好，一开始就感觉很舒服。
I adapted very well, I felt very comfortable from the beginning.
que me adapté muy bien, me sentí muy cómodo desde el principio.
我也开始了解自己不具备的另一面。
I also began to know another side of myself that I didn't have.
Empecé a conocer también otra faceta mía que no tenía.
总是进去，他已经习惯了打球。
of always going inside and he was very used to playing.
de ir siempre para adentro y estaba muy acostumbrado a jugar.
线始终连接到背面并始终完成拍摄中心
with the line always attached to the back and always finish shooting center when
con la línea siempre pegada a la espalda y bueno terminar tirando siempre centro cuando
例如，我在本菲卡的三年...
I was at Benfica, for example, the three years I had...
Estaba en el Benfica, por ejemplo, los tres años que tuve que tuve a...
她袭击了卡多佐，卡多佐在该区域内是致命的，而且刚刚进入头部。
She attacked Cardoso who was lethal inside the area and it was just getting in the head there.
atacó a la Cardoso que era letal adentro del área y era solo meterse ahí en la cabeza.
你和莫伊相处得怎么样？
How did you get along with Moe?
¿Cómo te llevaste con Moe?
什么是角色？
What is a character?
Que es un personaje.
如此壮观，事实是它是多么壮观......
As spectacular, the truth is how spectacular it is...
Como espectacular, la verdad que espectacular es un...
他是一个不可思议的人，100%的顽固分子。
He is an incredible person, 100% die-hard.
Es una persona increíble, con el jugador a muerte al 100%.
如果你把自己100给他，他就会给你生命。
If you give yourself 100 to him, he gives you life.
Si vos te brindás al 100 a él, él te da la vida.
那三年我相处得很好所以...
and I got along very well those three years so...
y yo me llevé muy bien esos tres años así que...
我对他没什么好说的，他很出色。
I have nothing bad to say about him, he is spectacular.
No tengo nada malo que decir de él, es espectacular.
你对皇马和巴萨的经历如何？
How did you experience those Real Madrid and Barcelona?
¿Cómo viviste esos Real Madrid y Barcelona?
南非的世界冠军几乎拉屎了自己，一方面是哈维……
In which the world champions in South Africa almost shit themselves, on the one hand Xavi...
En los que los campeones del mundo en Sudáfrica casi se cagan a trompadas, de un lado Xavi...
普约尔、皮克，另一边塞尔吉奥·拉莫斯……
Puyol, Piqué, on the other side Sergio Ramos...
Puyol, Piqué, del otro lado Sergio Ramos...
啊，大海，阿韦洛亚。
o sea, Arbeloa.
比方说，你和皮帕一起在马德里。
You, let's say, were with Pippa in Madrid.
Vos, digamos, estabas con Pippa en el Madrid.
在巴萨，哈维尔·马斯切拉诺也在场，瓜迪奥拉的新闻发布会也在场，国王杯决赛之间的那四场比赛他们都赢了......
At Barça, Javier Mascherano was also there, Guardiola's press conference, those four games between the Copa del Rey final that they won...
en el Barça, también estaba Javier Mascherano, la conferencia de prensa de Guardiola, esos cuatro partidos entre la final de Copa del Rey que ganan...
我们在梅斯塔利亚时，巴勃罗·帕拉迪斯（Pablo Paradis）穿过你的中锋，由来自 9 人组的克里斯蒂亚诺（Cristiano）进球。
We were at Mestalla with Pablo Paradis through your center, goal by Cristiano from Head of 9.
Estábamos nosotros en Mestalla con Pablo Paradis por centro tuyo, gol de Cristiano de Cabeza de 9.
这两场欧冠比赛...
The two Champions League games...
Los dos partidos de Champions...
那是一场战争，作为阿根廷人和你们，尤其是你们那 20 天的生活，这太疯狂了。
That was a war and let's say as Argentinians and you in particular how you lived those 20 days, it was crazy.
fue una guerra eso y ustedes digamos como argentinos y vos en particular cómo viviste esos 20 días que fue una locura
大流行病。
of the pandemic.
de la pandemia.
事实是它没有被理解。
The truth is that it was not understood.
La verdad que no se entendía.
在选择中，他们似乎都是朋友，而且......
In the selection it seemed that they were all friends and...
En la selección parecía que eran todos amigos y...
他们为任何前来的团队提供乘车服务。
and they gave a ride to any team that came.
y le daban un paseo a cualquier selección que venía.
然后当他们互相比赛时，他们后退，他们互相攻击，他们……
and then when they played against each other, they backed off, they hit each other, they...
y después cuando jugaban en contra se recagaban la patada, se pegaban piñas, se...
但好吧，这也是其中之一
but well, it was also one of the things that
pero bueno, era también una de las cosas que
毛已经在马德里每个人的头脑中实施了这一点
that Mau had implemented in the heads of each of those in Madrid
que había implementado Mau en la cabeza de cada uno de los de Madrid
击败巴萨的唯一方法就是这样。
The only way to beat that Barça was that way.
La única manera de ganarle a ese Barça era de esa manera.
击球、得分、跑动比他们更多，并利用我们必须得分的机会，因为之后
hitting, scoring, running more than them and taking advantage of the chance we had to score because after
pegando, metiendo, corriendo más que ellos y aprovechar la posibilidad que teníamos de gol porque después
在那一刻，不说谎，很明显你正经历着一场可怕的旅程
At that moment it was, not to lie, it was obvious that you were in for a terrible ride
en ese momento era, no hay que mentir, era obvio que te pegaban un paseo terrible
就像他们在第一场比赛中击中我们一样，他们让我们成为了五人。
like they hit us in the first game in the Card No, they made us five.
como nos pegaron el primer partido en el Card No, que nos hicieron cinco.
我不认为我一生中没有一场比赛是我看不到球的。
I don't think there was a game in my life when I didn't see the ball.
Creo que no hubo un partido en mi vida que no veía la pelota.
想要压迫并给我们一个坏球是一件令人难以置信的事情，但是......
Wanting to press and giving us a bad ball was an incredible thing but...
llegar a querer presionar y nos daba mala pelota era una cosa increíble pero...
但是，在那场比赛之后我们意识到情况有所不同。
But well, after that game we realized that it was different.
Pero bueno, a partir de ese partido nos dimos cuenta de que era de otra manera.
我们开始以不同的方式做事，事情也开始以不同的方式发生......
And we started doing it differently and that started to happen differently...
Y empezamos a hacer de otra manera y eso de otra manera empezó a...
导致他把菠萝拉到田里。
to lead to him shitting a pineapple on the field.
a llevar a que se cague una piña dentro de la cancha.
你和利奥和皮帕谈论这个问题是因为你们是竞争对手，但这更多的是西班牙人之间的问题。
And you and Leo and Pippa talked about it because you were rivals, but it was more of a question between Spaniards.
Y ustedes con Leo y Pippa hablaban de eso porque eran rivales, pero era más una cuestión entre españoles.
不，是的，有一瞬间我很害怕他们会伤害……
No, yes, for a moment I was afraid that they would injure...
No, sí, yo por un momento tenía miedo que lo lesionen a...
对于矮人来说，我最担心的是他出事，而不是其他事情，你明白吗？
With the dwarf, I was more worried about nothing happening to him than anything else, you see?
al enano, yo me preocupaba más por que no le pase nada que por otra cosa, ¿viste?
因为事实是，是的，那是……
because the truth is, yes, it was...
porque la verdad que sí, era...
还有一场梅斯塔利亚的比赛，决赛中是踢踢踢球的比赛
There is also a Mestalla game when in that final it was kick and kick
hay partida de Mestalla también cuando en esa final era patada y patada
好吧，在这场决赛中他们把我淘汰了
well, in this final they throw me out
bueno yo en esta final que me echan
他踢了跟我们作对的利奥。
He kicked Leo, who was going against us.
Le pego la patada a Leo, que se nos iba de contra.
没什么，我踢了他，然后我站起来告诉他，对不起，但如果他们不把你打倒，他们就无法进球。
And nothing, I kicked him and then I went to get up and told him, sorry, but if they didn't take you down, they couldn't score the goal.
Y nada, le pegué la patada y después fui a levantar y le dije, perdonadano, pero si no te bajaban, no podían hacer el gol.
我别无选择
I had no other option
no me quedaba otra opción
他们把我扔了出去，过了两秒、三秒，莉莉叔叔踢了球，比赛就结束了。
There they threw me out and it was two seconds, three seconds that Uncle Lili kicked and the game ended.
ahí me echaron y fueron dos segundos, tres segundos que patearon el tío Lili y terminó el partido.
没有别的办法，只能这样玩，根本停不下来。
There was no other option, it was to play that way, it was impossible to stop.
No quedaba otra, era jugar de esa manera, era imposible parar.
那天你打进了克里斯蒂安的球，但你射门的是曾经的中锋。
That day you score the Christian goal, but you shoot the Once center.
Ese día hacés el gol cristiano, pero vos tirando el centro de Once.
是的，因为我认为在那场比赛中，有一段时间我们最终以两人领先的方式结束比赛。
Yes, because I think that in that game there was a moment when we ended up playing with two up.
Sí, porque creo que en ese partido hubo un momento en el que terminamos jugando con dos arriba.
或者只有克里斯蒂亚诺一人，我作为乐队。
Or with Cristiano alone and me as the band.
O con Cristiano solo y yo por banda.
然后我们都有办法了，这就是事情结束的原因。
and then we all had the means, that's why it ended.
y después teníamos todos medios, por eso terminó.
事实上，在那场决赛中，替补席上的有PIPA、贝约尔的本泽马亚。
In fact, in that final, they are on the bench, PIPA, Benzemaia from Bayor.
De hecho esa final, están en el banco, PIPA, Benzemaia de Bayor.
这三人被排除在外，那就是尤文图斯 9 号克里斯蒂亚诺。
The three were left out and it was Cristiano Juventus 9.
Los tres quedaron afuera y fue Cristiano Juventus 9.
是的，是的，是的。
Yes, yes, yes.
Sí, sí, sí.
它试图从他手中夺走球，这是不可能的。
It was trying to get the ball from him, which was impossible.
Era intentar sacarle la pelota, que igual era imposible.
但我们尝试过并试图反对它
but we tried that and we tried to go against it
pero intentamos eso e intentamos salir en alguna de contra
在那一刻我们用头球攻入了那个进球，你已经在那里结束了比赛。
At that moment we scored that goal with a header and you were already finishing the game there.
En ese momento hicimos ese gol de cabeza y ya estabas a terminar el partido ahí.
里奥和克里斯蒂亚诺之间的竞争现在时间更长、更个性化，你对此有何感受？
How did you experience the rivalry, now more extended in time and more personalized, between Leo and Cristiano?
¿Cómo viviste la rivalidad ya más extendida en el tiempo y más personalizada entre Leo y Cristiano?
成为两人的伴侣。
being a companion of both.
siendo compañero de los dos.
我可以想象这些问题，利奥谁更好，利奥·克里斯蒂亚诺，我认为利奥......
I can imagine the questions, Leo who is better, Leo Cristiano, I think Leo has...
me imagino las preguntas, Leo quién es mejor, Leo Cristiano, yo creo que Leo tiene...
作为一名足球运动员，克里斯蒂亚诺比克里斯蒂亚诺更有维度，克里斯蒂亚诺是一名出色的前锋，一名非凡的得分手，但我认为利奥......
more dimensions as a footballer than Cristiano, who is a tremendous striker, an extraordinary scorer, but I think Leo...
más dimensiones como futbolista de Cristiano, que es un delantero tremendo, un goleador extraordinario, pero creo que Leo...
他的比赛还有两三个额外的维度。
he has two or three additional dimensions to his game.
tiene dos o tres dimensiones adicionales a su juego.
但是，作为玩家，你是如何经历这一点以及如何分析它的呢？
But well, how did you experience that and how do you analyze it as players.
Pero bueno, vos cómo viviste eso y cómo lo analizás como jugadores.
不，我总是说同样的话，而且我会继续说下去。
No, I always said the same thing and I will continue to say it.
No, yo siempre dije lo mismo y lo voy a seguir diciendo.
对我来说他们是...
For me they are...
Para mí son...
历史上最好的两个，但很明显
the two best in history, but it is obvious that
los dos mejores que hubo en la historia, pero es obvio que
到目前为止最好的是利奥，不仅仅是因为他有八个球。
that the best by far is Leo, not only because of the eight balls he has.
que el mejor lejos es el Leo, no solamente por los ocho balones que tiene.
因为他比克里斯蒂亚诺有很大的优势，而且在所有方面，因为
and because he has a very big advantage over Cristiano, but also for everything, because
y porque le saca una ventaja muy grande a Cristiano, sino también por todo, porque
因为基督徒的事情就是工作、工作、工作，而另一件事是……
Because the Christian thing is to work, work, work and the other thing is...
Porque lo cristiano es trabajar, trabajar, trabajar y lo del otro es...
纯粹的品质是上帝赐予你的。
Pure quality is what God gave you.
Calidad pura es lo que Dios le dio.
他不会强迫自己做任何事。
He doesn't force himself for anything.
No se fuerza por nada.
你不必做任何事情就能成为最好的。
You don't have to do anything to be the best.
no tiene que hacer nada para poder ser el mejor.
他一直要做的就是努力工作、健身
what he always had to do was work hard, gym
lo que tuvo que hacer siempre fue trabajar duro, gimnasio
总是做出定义，总是想要更多，更多，更多，矮人。
Always making definition, always wanting more, more, more, the dwarf.
Siempre estar haciendo definición, siempre el querer más, más, más, el enano.
你看到他，就好像你在和他的朋友一起玩，他很享受。
You see him and it's as if you are playing with his friends, he enjoys it.
Vos lo ves y es como si estás jugando con sus amigos, él disfruta.
足球，他就是这么做的，这就是我的原因
football and he does it that way that's why for me
el fútbol y lo hace de esa manera por eso para mí
毫无疑问，两者之间存在如此大的差异
It is such a big difference between one and the other and without a doubt
es la diferencia tan grande entre un y el otro y sin duda
狮子座与任何人都没有可比性，也不可能与他相比。
Leo has no comparison with anyone, it is not possible to compare him.
que Leo no tiene comparación con nadie, no es posible compararlo.
狮子座，他很有竞争力，他不喜欢失去任何东西。
He's competitive, Leo, he doesn't like to lose anything.
Es competitivo, Leo, no le gusta perder a nada.
事实上，一切对他来说都是自然而然的。
Beyond the fact that everything comes naturally to him.
Más allá de que todo le sale naturalmente.
它是一种有竞争力的动物。
It is a competitive animal.
Es un animal competitivo.
是的，是的，事实上，一切对他来说都是自然而然的，这与他不争强好胜无关，他是有争胜心的，而且很明显……
Yes, yes, the fact that everything comes naturally to him has nothing to do with him not being competitive, he is competitive and it is obvious that...
Sí, sí, no tiene nada que ver que le salga todo natural a que no sea competitivo, es competitivo y es obvio que...
每年他都想赢得金球奖，但是……
that every year he wanted to win the Ballon d'Or, but...
que todos los años él quería ganar el Balón de Oro, pero...
但有些时候有时...
but there are moments that sometimes...
pero hay como momentos que yo a veces...
我发现有些时候你会看到他的情绪有些低落。
I saw that there were moments in which you saw that he was going down a little.
Veía como que eran momentos en el que vos veías que él bajaba un poco.
那是另一个长大的时候。
And that was when the other grew up.
Y era cuando el otro crecía.
就好像他说，好吧，现在我要停下来，现在我想要，现在我要停下来。
As if he said, well, now I'll stop, now I want, now I'll stop.
Como que él decía, bueno, ahora dejo, ahora quiero, ahora dejo.
就像他想要的时候一样。
It's like when he wants.
Es como cuando él quiere.
他想要并且他做到了，你明白我的意思吗？
He wants and he does it, do you understand me?
Él quiere y él lo hace, ¿me entendés?
因为这一切都是那么自然，对他来说一切都是那么容易。
Because since it's all so natural, it's all so easy for him.
Porque como es todo tan natural, es todo tan fácil para él.
现在你已经37岁了，你仍然可以看到他们。
You still see them now at 37 years old.
Los seguís viendo ahora con 37 años.
佯攻、佯攻、佯攻、佯攻，他们最终都倒在了地板上，并以与他相同的方式结束了比赛
feint, feint, feint, feint and they all end up on the floor and end up defining in the same way as he does
amaga, amaga, amaga, amaga y todos terminan en el piso y terminan definiendo de la misma manera que hace
15、16年前，你发现一切都很自然，都是他。
15, 16 years ago, then you realize that it's all natural, it's all him.
15, 16 años atrás, entonces te das cuenta que es todo natural, es todo de él.
当他想要的时候他就会这么做，当他有一天想要的时候......
And when he wants he does it, when he wants the other day...
Y que cuando él quiere lo hace, cuando él quiere el otro día...
很高兴他们出局对阵亚特兰大
Good that they are out against Atlanta
bueno que quedan afuera contra el atlanta
他用头球攻入一球，如果你看到了，飞行员就会抓住它并离开。
He scored a goal with a header, which if you see, the pilot is going to grab it and go.
hizo un gol de cabeza, que si vos ves va a agarrar la pilota y va.
不，他去了这个地区，因为他看到中锋即将到来，他就去带头。
And no, he went to the area because he saw that the center was going to come and he went and headed it.
Y no, él fue al área porque veía que iba a venir el centro y fue y soltó de cabeza.
他想要它，就像球朝他的方向发展一样，他就像一块磁铁
He wants it and it's like the ball goes his way, he's a magnet
él quiere y es como que la pelota le va, es un imán
是这样的，但很明显它是有竞争力的，让我们看看现在它被排除在外的例子
It is like that, but it is obvious that it is competitive and let's see for example now that it was left out
es así, pero es obvio que es competitivo y a ver por ejemplo ahora que quedó fuera
很明显她现在发烧了，事实上镜头聚焦在她去更衣室的路上
It is obvious that now she had a fever that she must have had, in fact the camera focuses on her going to the locker room
es obvio que ahora tenía una calentura que debió haber tenido, es más la cámara la enfoca yendo al vestuario
是的，是的，很明显，很明显他发烧得很厉害，什么也没有，会有
And yes, yes, it is obvious, it is obvious that he had a terrible fever and nothing, there will be
Y sí, sí, es obvio, es obvio que habrá tenido una calentura terrible y nada, habrá
我让时间流逝，然后上传一些东西并说赛季结束了很好
I let time pass and then upload something and say it's good that the season is over
dejado pasar el tiempo para después subir algo y poner que bueno que se terminó la temporada
等等，但很明显，这一定对他造成了很大的伤害，因为……
and all that, but it is obvious that it must have hurt him a lot because...
y todo eso, pero es obvio que le habrá dolido muchísimo porque...
因为年复一年，你想要的只是……
Because year after year all you want is...
Porque año tras año lo único que quieres es...
赢得目标，继续获胜，继续获胜，这就是为什么他是历史上获胜最多的人。
win objectives and keep winning and keep winning and well that's why he is the winningest in history.
ganar objetivos y seguir ganando y seguir ganando y bueno por eso es el más ganador de la historia.
你还记得第一次见到Leo时的情景吗？
Do you remember the first time you saw him when you met Leo?
¿Te acordás la primera vez que lo viste cuando lo conociste a Leo?
我第一次见到她是在奥运会上。
The first time I saw her was at the Olympic Games.
La primera vez que la vi fue en los Juegos Olímpicos.
到北京，很好，他们留下了它，他们没有留下它，嗯，这是......
to Beijing, it's good that they left it, that they didn't leave it and well, it was...
a Beijing, que bueno que lo dejaban, que no lo dejaban y bueno, fue...
当我看到他、遇见他并能够与他交谈时，没有什么感觉
It was when I saw him and met him and was able to talk to him and nothing was a sensation
fue cuando lo vi y lo conocí y pude hablar con él y nada fue una sensación
对我来说是独一无二的，能够做到这一点真是令人难以置信
unique for me, it was something incredible to be able
única para mí, fue algo increíble poder
能够和他分享奥运会，能够见到他，能够和他聊天，和他在一起。
to be able to share the Olympic games with him, to be able to see him, to be able to chat with him, to be with him.
poder compartir con él unos juegos olímpicos, poder verlo, poder charlar con él, estar con él.
事实上，它非常特别。
The truth is that it was very special.
La verdad que fue muy especial.
两人的关系什么时候变得更牢固或者合拍了？
And when did the relationship become stronger or did they click?
¿Y la relación cuándo se afianza o hicieron clic de entrada?
在那届奥运会上，因为我的房间......
And there in those Olympic Games, because my room was...
Y ahí en esos Juegos Olímpicos, porque mi habitación era...
Pocho 和我在一起，那是音乐室、伴侣室、房间
Pocho with me and it was the music room, the mate room, the room
Pocho conmigo y era la habitación de la música, la habitación de mate, la habitación
最重要的是，比赛结束后我们就留在那里。
of everything, after the games we stay there.
de todo, después de los partidos quedarnos ahí.
当时我们有一块他们买的电池
At the time we had a battery that they had bought
en el momento tuvimos una batería que habían comprado
一切都还好，被关了一个月。
It was all there and well, being locked up for a month.
Era todo ahí y bueno, estar un mes encerrado.
而一切都让我们有机会认识他，开始……
and everything gave us the opportunity to get to know him, to start...
y todo nos dio la posibilidad de conocerlo, de empezar a...
他们已经建立了友谊，从那里很明显......
They already formed a friendship and from there it was obvious that...
formaron ya una relación de amistad y a partir de ahí quedó, es obvio que...
那个人从来没有想过能够在国家队一起度过16年，但是……
that one never thought of being able to spend 16 years together in the national team, but...
que uno nunca pensó en poder después estar 16 años juntos en la selección, pero...
在那些时刻，充分享受它，因为你不知道明天是否会回来。
In those moments, enjoy it to the fullest because you don't know if you'll have it back tomorrow.
En esos momentos disfruta al máximo porque no sabes si mañana lo vas a tener de vuelta.
当然，随着时间的推移，我们所有人都会遇到一些事情......
Of course things happen to all of us over time...
Por supuesto que a todos nos pasan cosas con el paso del tiempo...
我们是父母，我们是孩子，现在我们是父母，还有那些事情
We are parents, we were children, now we are parents and those things too
somos papás, éramos hijos, ahora somos papás y esas cosas también
随着我们职业的进步，它们就会发生。
They occur as we advance in our professions.
van ocurriendo en la medida que avanzamos en nuestras profesiones.
你认为开始成为一名父亲并承担其他责任这一事实对他有何影响？
How do you think the fact of starting to be a father, assuming other responsibilities, influenced him?
¿Cómo crees que a él le influyó el hecho de empezar a ser papá, asumiendo otras responsabilidades?
他的团队领导力超出了他在球场上一直以来的表现。
in what his group leadership is, beyond what he has always been on the field.
en lo que es su liderazgo grupal, más allá de lo que siempre ha sido dentro de la cancha.
我认为这一切对他帮助很大。
And I think all that helped him a lot.
Y yo creo que lo ayudó muchísimo todo eso.
这对他帮助很大...
It helped him a lot...
Lo ayudó mucho a...
也要改变。
to change too.
a cambiar también.
我相信他一直拥有它，他一直都是，但从来没有
I believe that he always had it, he always was, but never
Yo creo que él siempre lo tuvo, siempre fue, pero nunca
这从来不是谈论，也不是离开去做，例如现在的事情。
It was never about talking, it was never about going off and doing, for example, what it is now.
Nunca era de hablar, nunca era de largarse a hacer por ejemplo como es ahora.
但我认为他内心有这一切，因为他在谈话或其他方面与我们相处得很好。
But I think he had all that inside because he was good with us in talks or whatever.
pero yo creo que todo eso dentro lo tenía porque bueno con nosotros en charlas o lo que sea
你看到了它，或者当我们开会时你看到了它，但是......
You saw it or when we had meetings you saw it but...
vos lo veías o cuando hacíamos reuniones vos lo veías pero...
但对于局外人来说，我认为也不可能
but then for the outsider, I don't think it's also possible that
pero después para el de afuera no yo creo que también capaz que
因为关于他的一切言论，或者因为他们也伤害了他。
because of everything that was said about him or because of how they hurt him too.
por todo lo que se decía de él o por cómo lo lastimaban también.
他坚持以同样的方式继续下去并达到
he clung to continuing in the same way and to achieve
él se aferraba a seguir de la misma manera y de lograr
在某些时候，一切都以同样的方式，不会改变，因为......
at some point everything in the same way, not to change because...
en algún momento todo de la misma manera, de no cambiar porque...
因为他们告诉他他没有唱国歌，因为他们告诉他他没有说话，或者因为他没有......
because they told him that he didn't sing the anthem, because they told him that he didn't speak or because he didn't...
porque le decían que no cantaba el himno, porque le decían que no hablaba o porque no...
他们说他没有爪子。
They said he had no claw.
Decían que no tenía garra.
如果以后你在巴萨见到他并且......
If later, you saw him at Barça and...
Si después, vos lo veías en el Barça y...
他拥有一切，他展示了一切，而在国家队，缺少的是力量
and he had everything, he showed everything and in the national team what was missing was power
y lo tenía todo, lo demostraba todo y en la selección lo que faltaba era poder
实现它，能够拿出那个背包
achieve it, being able to take out that backpack that
lograrlo, el poder sacar esa mochila que
之前带来的，不幸的是......
that the previous ones brought, which unfortunately...
que traían los anteriores, que lamentablemente...
我们经过了其他人，背包装在一个人身上，然后又装在另一个人身上，然后又装在另一个人身上。
We passed others and the backpack fits on one, then on another, then on another.
Fuimos pasando otros y la mochila se le va quedando a uno, después a otro, después a otro.
正如我们所说的或正如我们现在所说的，对吧？
as we said or as we say now, right?
como decíamos nosotros o como decimos ahora, ¿no?
因为别人，最后，背包……
Because of others, in the end, the backpack...
Por culpa de los demás, al final, la mochila...
其他人正在携带它，而我们已经拥有了它。
Others are carrying it and we already had it.
la van cargando los demás y ya la teníamos nosotros.
没什么，事实是，所有这一切的好处是它也已经
and nothing, the truth is that the good thing about all of that is that it also already
y nada la verdad que lo bueno de todo eso es que también ya
那个背包被拿出来，后来的每个人都不再拥有它，他开始……
That backpack was taken out and everyone who came after no longer had it and he started...
Esa mochila se sacó y todos los que vienen después ya no la tienen y él empezó a...
能够改变并开始展示他本来的样子。
to be able to change and begin to show what he really already was.
a poder cambiar y empezar a demostrar lo que realmente ya era.
但他并没有表现得那么多。
but he didn't show it that much.
pero no lo demostraba tanto.
你改变了你的饮食习惯、你的训练习惯、你的休息习惯吗？或者一切都变得更好了吗？
Have you changed your eating habits, your training habits, your rest habits, or has everything turned out better?
¿Has cambiado hábitos de alimentación, de entrenamiento, de descanso o todo te ha salido
总是那么自然。
always so natural.
siempre tan natural.
从什么意义上说？
In what sense?
¿En qué sentido?
如果你停止吃一些可能对你没有帮助的食物......
If you stopped eating some foods that perhaps weren't helping you...
Si dejaste de comer algunas comidas que quizás no te ayudaban...
如果你更加重视休息、训练、部位，如果你愿意的话，可以增加力量。
If you give more emphasis to rest, to training, to the part, if you want, more strength.
si le das más bola al descanso, al entrenamiento, a la parte, si querés, más de fuerza.
不，不，事实是一切都是一样的，我从未改变过任何东西。
No, no, the truth is that it's always the same, I never changed anything.
No, no, la verdad que siempre igual, nunca cambié nada.
是的，从...
Yes, from...
Sí, a partir de...
我在主场对阵委内瑞拉的比赛中也说过这一点
I also told it from the match with Venezuela at home
que también lo conté a partir del partido con Venezuela de local
在我再次撕裂自己的纪念碑中。
in the monumental that I tear myself apart again.
en el monumental que me vuelvo a desgarrar.
我现在不太记得那一年了。
I don't remember the year well now.
No me acuerdo bien el año ahora.
我认为那是在第二次输掉美洲杯之后。
It was when I think it was after the second lost Copa América.
fue cuando creo que fue después de la segunda Copa América perdida.
就在那时我开始...
That's when I started...
fue cuando empecé a...
我没有开始，但我又回去和那些在建筑上工作的人一起工作......
I didn't start, but I went back to work again with the people who worked on buildings and...
No empecé, sino volví otra vez a trabajar con la gente que trabajaba de edificios y...
和营养和良好的一切
and nutrition and good and everything that
y de nutrición y bueno y de todo lo que
对于一名足球运动员来说，这意味着什么，并且能够变得更好。
what it entails for a soccer player and to be able to be better.
lo que conlleva para un jugador de fútbol y para poder estar mejor.
我在各方面都感觉好多了。
and that I feel better in every way.
y que me sienta mejor en todo sentido.
这是我改变的唯一对我有帮助的事情，嗯，从……
That was the only thing I changed that helped me and well, from...
fue eso lo único que cambié y que me ayudó y que bueno, a partir de...
从那一刻起，我受伤的次数开始减少，瞬间的次数也减少了很多。
From that moment on I began to have many fewer injuries, many fewer moments.
De ese momento empecé a tener muchas menos lesiones, muchos menos momentos.
对我来说很难，总是受伤
hard for me it was always having injuries and
duros para mí que era siempre tener lesiones y
在那里我的生活发生了很大的变化。
and life for me changed a lot there.
y la vida para mí ahí cambió muchísimo.
那是在一场非常好的表现之后，那就是瑞士戈拉中超……
that came after a very good performance, that is, the Swiss Gola CSL...
que venían después de una muy buena actuación, o sea, la CSL gola suiza...
在美洲杯中对阵比利时，同样的事情也会发生，你有
crack against belgium in the america's cup the same thing happens you have a
crack contra bélgica en la copa américa pasa lo mismo tenés una
一场精彩的半决赛，然后你在决赛中受伤了。
great semi-final match and then you get hurt in the final.
gran partido de semifinal y después te lastimás en la final.
作为...？
As...?
¿Cómo...?
你为此付出了精神上的努力，如果你寻找一些解释，以便稍后你可以回去与那个对你帮助很大的团队一起工作。
You worked mentally for that and if you looked for some explanation so that later you could go back to work with that team that helped you so much.
trabajaste mentalmente para eso y si buscaste alguna explicación para después sí volver a laburar con ese equipo que tanto te ayudó.
不，事实是他受了很多苦。
No, the truth is that he suffered a lot.
No, la verdad que sufrió muchísimo.
这些年他受了很多很多很多。
All those years he suffered a lot, a lot, a lot.
Todos esos años sufrió un montón, montón, montón.
呃……
Ehhh...
我无法用言语来描述这些年来发生在我身上的一切。
There are no words for me to describe everything that happened to me during all those years.
No hay palabras para que pueda describir todo lo que me pasó durante todos esos años.
从我的脑海里看，这已经是某件事了
from my head, it was already something
de mi cabeza, ya era algo
有些东西已经卡在这里了，我出不来，它正在杀死我，因为……
something that was already stuck here, that I couldn't get out, that was killing me because...
algo que ya estaba metido acá, que no podía sacarlo, que me estaba matando porque...
因为我知道每次我来...
because I knew that every time I came...
porque sabía que cada vez que venía...
重要的比赛、决赛、之前进行得很精彩的比赛，总是
important matches, finals, previous matches that had been going spectacularly, always
partidos importantes, finales, partidos anteriores que venían andando espectacular, siempre
发生了什么事，总是有问题。
something happened, there was always a problem.
pasaba algo, siempre tenía algún problema.
所有这些都让我头晕目眩，但后来慢慢地
and all that was messing with my head but well then little by little
y todo eso a mi me estaba líquiando la cabeza pero bueno después poco a poco
事情正在发生变化，我开始与这些人一起工作。
Things were changing, I started working with these people.
las cosas fueron cambiando, empecé a trabajar con esta gente.
当我 2000 年和 2011 年到达马德里时，他已经工作了。
who had already worked when I arrived at Madrid in 2000 and 2011.
que ya había trabajado cuando llegué al Madrid en el 2000 y 2011.
后来我停止了工作，因为这是你年轻时的典型想法。
Afterwards I stopped working because it's the typical thing you think because you're young.
Después dejé de trabajar porque es la típica que uno se piensa que porque es joven.
什么都没有发生，世界带你前进
nothing happens and the world takes you ahead
no pasa nada y te lleva el mundo por delante
没什么，事情不是那样的。
And nothing, it's not like that.
Y nada, no es así.
身体是...
The body is...
El cuerpo es...
它是一个人的工作工具，必须爱护它。
It is one's work tool and one has to take care of it.
es la herramienta de trabajo de uno y la tiene que cuidar.
就像任何人处理自己的工作一样，以他们做事的方式。
In the same way that anyone takes care of their work, in the way they do it.
De la misma manera que cualquiera cuida su trabajo, de la manera que lo haga.
事实上，在那些时刻我照顾了他，但不是100%。
And the truth is that in those moments I took care of him but not 100%.
y yo la verdad que en esos momentos lo cuidaba pero no al 100
并没有按照我的要求充分照顾他。
and not taking full care of him in the demands that I had.
y no cuidarlo al cien en las exigencias que yo tenía.
当时在马德里，在巴黎，在曼彻斯特，在一切事情上，
of being in Madrid at the time, in Paris, in Manchester, in everything,
de estar en Madrid en su momento, en el París, en el Manchester, en todo,
不断的压力，要赢，赢，赢，赢。
the constant pressure to win, win, win, win.
la presión constante de ganar, ganar, ganar, ganar.
所有这些导致我遇到了所有这些问题，但是好吧，从
and all that led me to have all those problems, but well, from
y todo eso me llevaba a tener todos esos problemas, pero bueno, a partir de
从那场最终在更衣室里哭泣的比赛开始
from that game that ended up crying in the locker room
de ese partido que termine llorando en el vestuario
我拿起电话，收到了我妻子的信息，她总是在那儿
I picked up the phone and I had the message from my wife who is the one who is always there
que agarré el teléfono y tenía el mensaje de mi mujer que es la que siempre está ahí
银行所有且永远存在的银行
banking all and the one that is always
bancando todas y la que está siempre
在峡谷脚下以各种方式睁开我的眼睛，她是那个再次告诉我的人
at the foot of the canyon to open my eyes in every way and she was the one who told me again
al pie del cañón para abrirme los ojos en todo sentido y fue la que volvió a decirme
我不希望你在没有和华金谈过话的情况下就回家，好吧……
I don't want you to get home without having spoken with Joaquín and well...
No quiero que llegues a casa sin que hayas hablado con Joaquín y bueno...
就在那时我再次打电话给他并告诉他我们必须开始工作，因为现在......
That's when I called him again and told him that we had to start working because now...
Fue ahí cuando volví a llamarlo otra vez y le dije que teníamos que empezar a trabajar porque ya...
我再也受不了了，我的头要爆炸了，我因受伤而腐烂了。
I can't take it anymore, my head is exploding, I'm rotten from getting injured.
Ya no puedo más, mi cabeza está explotada, estoy podrido de lesionarme.
我想要一劳永逸地感觉良好，我还有很多年的时间，我想要保持健康。
and I want to feel good once and for all, I still have many years ahead of me and I want to be well.
y quiero sentirme bien de una buena vez, me quedan muchos años todavía por delante y quiero estar bien.
从那时起我开始工作，从那时起我开始
and well from that I started to work and well that was when I started to
y bueno a partir de eso empecé a trabajar y bueno fue cuando cuando empecé a
减少伤害，每年一次，有时一次……
to have much fewer injuries, one per year, sometimes one and...
a tener muchísimas menos lesiones, una por año, a veces una y...
和一些不适，但这并不等于受伤，对我来说这很严重，因为通常我有
and some discomfort but it does not amount to injury and that for me is a lot because normally I had
y alguna molestia pero no llega a lesión y eso para mí es un montón porque normalmente tenía
一年三四次，甚至在重要时刻，他还割断了我的腿。
three or four a year and more at important moments and he cut my legs.
tres o cuatro por año y más en momentos importantes y me cortaba las piernas.
你也浪费了作为一名足球运动员的有用生命，你是否正在考虑退役，你是否正在为它设定一个日期，或者……？
And you have also wasted your useful life as a footballer, are you thinking about retirement, are you setting a date for it or...?
y además te has tirado la vida útil como futbolista, ¿pensás en el retiro, le ponés fecha o...?
在国家队度过一段时光后，你会享受更多的乐趣。
You are enjoying much more after what your time in the national team has been.
estás disfrutando mucho más después de lo que ha sido tu etapa en la selección.
不，事实并非如此，事实并非如此。
No, the truth is no, the truth is no.
No, la verdad que fecha no, la verdad que fecha no.
在我们在国家队赢得了一切之后，我更加享受了。
I'm enjoying it a lot more after everything we won in the national team.
Estoy disfrutando muchísimo más después de todo lo que ganamos en la selección.
就像在2021年拿出那个背包后
It's like after taking out that backpack in 2021
es como que después sacar esa mochila en el 2021
从那时起我开始更加享受它，以前并不是不喜欢它。
From then on I started to enjoy it much more, it wasn't that I didn't enjoy it before.
a partir de ahí empezar a disfrutar mucho más no era que antes no disfrutaba
但就像我总是对我所缺少的东西有刹车一样，那就是……
but like I always had that brake there of what I was missing, which was the...
sino como que siempre tenía ese freno ahí de lo que me faltaba, que era la...
随国家队获胜，但从那时起......
win with the national team, but from then on it's...
ganar con la selección, pero a partir de ahí es...
过去的这些年都是享受、快乐的岁月。
All these last years have been ones of enjoyment, of joy.
todos estos últimos años fue de disfrute, de alegría.
玩得开心，希望训练的日子到来，知道我确实有两天休息时间。
to have a good time, to want the day of training to arrive, to know that I do have two days off.
de pasarla bien, de querer que llegue el día del entrenamiento, de que sí tengo dos días libres.
自从我第三次离开他去训练后，他又回到了我身边。
Since I left him the third time to go to training, he came back to me again.
ya que lo deje el tercero para ir al entrenar de vuelta me volvió otra vez a
在我们在国家队赢得一切之后，给予我们生活的渴望。
to give that desire to live after everything we won in the national team.
a dar esas ganas de vivir después de todo lo que ganamos en la selección.
或者其他什么，现在我很享受它，而事实是我没有......
or anything, now I'm enjoying it and the truth is that I don't have...
ni nada, ahora estoy disfrutando y la verdad que no tengo...
我从来没有说过两年就这样了，不，不是真的。
I don't have a moment where I say two years and that's it, no, not really.
No tengo un momento en el decir ya dos años y listo, no, la verdad que no.
你想成为一名教练还是还很遥远？
Would you like to be a coach or is that still far away?
¿Te gustaría ser entrenador o todavía está lejos eso?
我正在做这门课，我正在做，但是......
I'm doing the course, I'm doing it, but...
Estoy haciendo el curso, estoy haciéndolo, pero...
但我这样做只是为了以防万一。
But I'm doing it just in case.
Pero lo estoy haciendo por si acaso.
我不知道，事实是，正如我告诉你的，从 30 年代开始，我开始以不同的方式看待足球，我开始分析，我开始看更多的比赛。
I don't know, the truth is, as I told you, from the 30's I started to see football differently, I started to analyze, I started to watch a lot more.
No sé, la verdad, como te dije, a partir de los 30's empecé a ver el fútbol diferente, empecé a analizar, empecé a ver mucho más.
一切都来自对方，不仅来自球员这边，而且……
Everything from the other side, not only from the player's side, but as...
Todo desde el otro lado, no solamente desde el lado del jugador, sino como...
教练怎么看他。
how a coach can see him.
como puede llegar a verle un entrenador.
但什么都没有，在那之前，我稍后会看到，我知道......
but nothing, until then, I'll see later, I know that...
pero nada, hasta ahí, después veré más adelante, sé que...
教练部分也更加困难，因为......
that the coaching part is also much more difficult because...
que la parte de entrenador también es mucho más difícil porque...
一切都比那些人需要更长、更多的时间……
Everything takes much longer, more time than those who...
se lleva mucho más tiempo todo, más tiempo que los que...
您回家时所训练的球员或球员
player or player you are trained you returned home on
jugador o de jugador vas entrenado volviste a tu casa el
教练和助理们以及其他一切，他们必须不断地观看视频、观察事物，花费更多的时间。
The coach with the assistants and everything, they have to keep watching videos, looking at things, spending much more time.
El entrenador con los ayudantes y todo, tienen que seguir mirando videos, mirando cosas, pasar mucho más tiempo.
事实是，如果我退休时，我希望......
And the truth is that if I retire when I do, I would like...
Y la verdad que si me retiro en el momento que lo haga, me gustaría...
也享受一点家庭时光，能够度过更多的时光，之后你将能够
also enjoy a bit of family, being able to spend many more moments and later on you will be able to
también disfrutar un poco de la familia, de poder pasar muchos más momentos y más adelante es capaz que
会发生什么。
what happens.
que se da.
说到教练，你们有安切洛蒂，我们有 DirecTV...
Speaking of coaches, you had Ancelotti, we had DirecTV...
Hablando de entrenadores, tuviste a Ancelotti, a nosotros nos tocó por DirectTV...
传送我的游戏 la acomode
transmit the game of me la acomode
transmitir el partido de me la acomode
另外那天我认为你打的是左路，也就是说，或者是10分勾手。
Also that day I think you played on the left, that is, or with a 10-point hook.
que además ese día creo que jugaste por la izquierda, o sea, o de engancho de 10.
搭配红色衬衫，可以是粉色，也可以是粉色。
and with the red shirt, it could be, or pink.
y con la camiseta roja, puede ser, o rosa.
不，那一方的头已经白了。
No, that party had a white head.
No, ese partido estaba con la cabecita blanca.
到了白色的那个。
To the white one.
A la blanca.
白色的抱歉，是的，那场比赛是的，但是是的，但是是的，那一年我们有
the white one sorry yes that match yes but yes but yes that year we had
la blanca perdón sí ese partido sí pero sí pero sí ese año teníamos
不，那一年我们没有红衬衫，或者我认为我们有。
No, that year we didn't have a red shirt, or I think we did.
No, ese año no teníamos camiseta roja, o me parece que sí.
或许也是如此，但是……
Maybe so too, but...
Puede ser que sí también, pero...
但不是那个政党，那个政党的目标是白人。
But not that party, that party had the white goal.
Pero ese partido no, ese partido tenía la blanca.
整个画面非常非常非常有趣
and the whole image was very very very funny
y fue muy muy muy graciosa toda la imagen
他们关注的是你的住宿条件、安切洛蒂的脸、你说的话、卡莱托说的话，谁不是今天的卡莱托。
They focus on you with the accommodation, Ancelotti's face, what you say, what Carletto says, who is not the Carletto of today.
te enfocan a vos con el acomodo, la cara de Ancelotti, lo que decís vos, lo que dice Carletto, que no es el Carletto de hoy.
这是歌曲的第一阶段。
It was the first stage of the song.
fue la primera etapa de la canto.
是的，事实是它有时对我有帮助，正如到处都指出的那样。
Yes, the truth is that it helped me at times when, as was already pointed out everywhere.
Sí, la verdad que me bancó en momentos en que como ya estaba señalado por todos lados.
我还有另一份，但是哦好吧
I had another one but oh well
tenía otra más pero bueno
当我出来的时候，就是我安定下来的那一刻，我想……
It was that moment when I settled when I came out, I think...
Fue ese momento en que me acomodé cuando salí, creo que...
如果我想做其中任何一个，我可以采取不同的方式。
If I had wanted to do any of that I could have done it differently.
Si hubiese querido hacer algo de eso también lo podría haber hecho de diferente manera.
在所有人面前做类似的事情。
and do something like that, in front of all the people.
y hacer algo así, adelante de toda la gente.
我不是那种会做这些事的人，事实是我真诚地
I'm not one to do those things and the truth is that sincerely
no soy de hacer esas cosas y la verdad que sinceramente
我已经安顿下来，但就在我离开的时候。
I had settled in, but it was just as I was leaving.
Me había acomodado, pero fue justo cuando estaba saliendo.
在我试图道歉之后什么也没有留下 我尝试过
and nothing was left there after I tried to apologize I tried
y nada quedó ahí después intenté pedir disculpas intenté
改变已经发生的一切，尝试做一些事情......
change everything that had happened, try to do things...
cambiar todo lo que había pasado, intentar hacer las cosas...
最好尝试让人们再次爱我、原谅我。
Better to try to get people to love me again, to forgive me.
Mejor intentar que la gente me vuelva a querer, que me perdone.
没有什么，他强迫我死。
And nothing, he forced me to die.
Y nada, él me bancó a morir.
老实说，不。
Honestly, no.
Sinceramente, no.
他没有让我死在那里。
He didn't let me die there.
No dejó que me muera ahí.
当时12月他们也想卖掉我。
At that time they also wanted to sell me in December.
En ese momento querían venderme también en diciembre.
摩纳哥当时支付了 8000 万，
to Monaco who paid I think 80 million at that time and
al Mónaco que pagaba creo que 80 millones en ese momento y
没什么，他想让我留下来，他寻找我，他最终为我找到了一个地方，因为他也有这个问题......
And nothing, he wanted me to stay and he looked for me, he ended up looking for a place for me because he also had that problem that...
Y nada, él quiso que me quede y me buscó, me terminó buscando un lugar porque también tenía ese problema de que...
克里斯蒂亚诺、本泽马和伊拜都在那里，没有地方踢球。
that Cristiano, Benzema and Ibai were there and there was no place to play.
de que estaba Cristiano, Benzema e Ibai y no tenía lugar para jugar.
没什么，我从来没有面对过屁股
and nothing, I never faced the ass
y nada, yo nunca le hice cara al culo
我对他缺乏尊重，我从来没有做过任何事情，我总是充满热情地训练，就像我在整个职业生涯中所做的那样。
I lacked respect for him, I never did anything, I always trained with enthusiasm, just as I always did my entire career.
le falté respeto, nunca nada, siempre entrené con ganas, igual como lo hice siempre toda mi carrera.
没什么，最后我找到了一个地方，因为从...
And nothing, in the end I ended up finding a place, because from...
Y nada, al final me terminé encontrando un lugar, porque a partir de...
一月、十二月、十二月底让我……
January, December, end of December made me...
de enero, diciembre, fin de diciembre me puso de...
中间，左边三个，什么也没有，那是……
in the middle with three on the left side and nothing, it was...
en el medio con tres por el lado izquierdo y nada, fue...
这是一个伟大的进球，因为那是辉煌的一年，我们赢得了冠军联赛。
It was a great goal because it was a spectacular year, we won the Champions League.
Fue un golazo porque fue un año espectacular, ganamos la Champions.
在那次住宿之后，没有什么是令人难以置信的
and nothing was incredible just after that accommodation I had
y nada fue increíble justo tuve después de eso del acomodo tuve
我们打了三场客场比赛，我想其中两场是客场对阵亚丝娜。
We played three away games, I think they were two against Asuna, away.
Tres partidos que jugábamos de visitante, creo que eran dos contra los Asuna, fuera.
他在中场打进了进球和一切。
and he had scored the goals and everything, playing there in the middle.
y había hecho los goles y todo, jugando ahí en el medio.
然后当他再次回来时，他召开了会议，他们再次问他，他说，就是这样，就是这样。
And then when he came back again, he had the conference and they asked him again and he said, that's it, that's it.
Y como que después cuando volvió otra vez, él tuvo la conferencia y le volvieron a preguntar y él dijo, ya está, ya.
已经结束了，我们必须把它剪掉，我不知道这样的话是什么。
It's already over, we have to cut it off. I don't know what something like that said.
ya ya pasó ya tenemos que cortar con eso no sé qué algo así dijo
没什么，那天有一对夫妇......
And nothing, that day there were a couple or another...
Y nada, ese día hubo un par que otro...
当我抓住球时，我在体育场里尖叫起来，但是......
I screamed there in the stadium when I grabbed the ball but...
chiflido ahí en el estadio cuando agarraba la pelota pero...
但就是那场比赛，然后就被砍掉了。
But it was that game and then it was cut.
Pero fue ese partido y después ya se cortó.
2014年有两件事非常重要。
In 2014 there are two very important episodes.
En 2014 hay dos episodios muy importantes.
一是你缺席世界杯决赛。
One is your absence in the World Cup final.
Uno es tu ausencia en la final del Mundial.
另一个是销售。
and the other is the sale.
y el otro es la venta.
我的意思是，詹姆斯·罗德里格斯在世界杯上表现出色，他们最终买下了他，你会得到它。
I mean, James Rodríguez has a great World Cup, they end up buying him and you're going to get it.
O sea, James Rodríguez hace una gran Copa del Mundo, terminan comprándolo y vos te vas a dar.
曼联。
a Manchester United.
如果皇马2014年写的那封信在2022年到达，那么2024年。
if that letter that Real Madrid writes in 2014 arrives in 2022, 2024.
si esa carta que escribe Real Madrid en 2014 llega en 2022, 2024.
你的反应也一样吗？
Is your reaction the same?
¿Tu reacción es la misma?
是的，完全正确。
Yes, exactly.
Sí, exacto.
无论如何我都会打破它。
I break it anyway.
La rompo igual.
还有和教练的关系……
and the relationship with the coach so that...
y la relación con el entrenador para que...
可以改变他所做的决定，亚历杭德罗·萨贝拉。
can change the decision that he had made, that of Alejandro Sabella.
pueda cambiar la decisión que él había tomado, la de Alejandro Sabella.
这更多的是艾尔的决定。
That was more of Ale's decision.
Eso ya fue más una decisión de Ale.
加上我的一点点，对吧？
with a little of mine, right?
con un poco de mía, ¿no?
假设我做了一切来达到最后的一切
let's say I did everything to get to that final everything
digamos yo hice todo para llegar a esa final todo
我早上、下午、晚上都训练
I trained in the morning, in the afternoon and at night
entrené por la mañana, por la tarde y por la noche
每天三次训练三次
three times three times a day training
tres veces tres veces en el día entrenando
插入手指，当他们对我做事时哭泣，一切。
inserting fingers, crying when they did things to me, everything.
metiendo dedos, llorando cuando me hacían las cosas, todo.
无论如何，都要依靠一千件事才能到达那里。
banking on a thousand things to be able to get there no matter what.
bancándome mil cosas para poder llegar como sea.
我什么也没感觉到，它不在那儿，它不在那儿 100
and nothing I felt that it was not there that it was not there 100
y nada yo sentía que no estaba que no estaba el 100
如果我们冒一点风险，那就是 80%、90%。
which was 80%, 90%, if we risked a little.
que estaba un 80%, 90%, si arriesgamos un poco.
没什么，我告诉了他真相......
And nothing, I told him the truth...
Y nada, yo le dije la verdad...
我拥有他，我拥有他，我拥有一切，我非常感激他，我非常爱他，他是一个......
I have him, I had him, I have everything, I appreciate him very much, I loved him a lot, he was a...
Le tengo, le tenía, le tengo todo, muchísimo aprecio, lo quería un montón, fue una la...
在那些同样支持我的人中，他是第一个给我的人
Of the people who also supported me a lot, he was the first one who gave me the
de las personas que también me bancó muchísimo fue el primero que me dio la
队长绶带也是国家队的，是继...之后的第三条。
the captain's ribbon also of the national team, being the third after...
la cinta de capitán también de la selección siendo el tercero después de...
来自哈维，来自利奥……对我来说这就是一切，好吗？
from Javi, from Leo... For me it was everything, okay?
de Javi, de Leo... Para mí fue todo, ¿vale?
而那一刻我并没有...
And at that moment I didn't...
Y yo en ese momento no...
我不想让他失望，我诚实地告诉了他真相。
I didn't want to let him down and I honestly told him the truth.
No quería defraudarlo y sinceramente le dije la verdad.
他渗透到了我的体内，无论发生什么，如果一切都破裂了，什么也不会发生。
that he infiltrated me, that no matter what happened, if everything broke, nothing would happen.
que me infiltraba, que pase lo que pase, si me rompía todo, no pasaba nada.
我不在乎，在某个时候我会康复，但我也不想……
I don't care, at some point later I was going to recover, but I didn't want to either...
Me da exactamente igual, en algún momento después me iba a recuperar, pero yo no quería tampoco...
参加一场你必须 100% 投入的游戏
being in a game where you have to be 100%
estar en un partido en el que tenés que estar al 100%
只为了想参加决赛的自我
and only for the ego of wanting to play in that final
y solamente por el ego de querer jugar esa final
不考虑团队，不考虑还有另一个100的队友可以做到。
Not thinking about the team, not thinking that there is another teammate who is at 100 and who can do it.
No estar pensando en el equipo, no estar pensando en que hay otro compañero que está al 100 y que lo pueda hacer.
比我更好，我什么也没告诉他，他就是这么理解的，最后他
better than me and I told him nothing like that and he understood it that way and in the end he
mejor que yo y nada se lo dije así y lo entendió de esa manera y al final él
他最终决定让我去银行，这对我来说似乎是正确的，因为
He ended up making the decision for me to go to the bank and it seemed correct to me because
él terminó tomando la decisión de que vaya al banco y me pareció correcta porque
这场比赛非常精彩。
The match was spectacular.
El partido fue espectacular.
我们度过了一场令人难以置信的决赛，我们理应获胜。
We had an incredible final in which we deserved to win.
Hicimos una final increíble en la que merecíamos ganar.
好吧，这就是我们之前讨论过的：
and well, that's what we had talked about before:
y bueno es lo que habíamos hablado antes son
一些小事情可能会让你成为世界冠军。
little things that can make you world champion or not.
pequeñas cosas que te puede hacer campeón del mundo o no.
他们采取了快速的一方，我们分心了
they took a quick side we were distracted
ellos sacaron un lateral rápido estábamos distraídos
他们最终进球了，就这样，比赛结束了，就是这样。
and they end up scoring a goal and that's it, the game is over, that's how it is.
y te terminan haciendo un gol y ya está, se termina el partido, es así.
事情就是这样发生的，但我不会改变当时我所说的和所做的一切。
And it happened that way, but I wouldn't change anything I said and what I did at that moment.
Y se dio de esa manera, pero no cambiaría nada de lo que dije y lo que hice en ese momento.
是...
Y...
在开始演讲之前我告诉过你我看了 Netflix 的连续剧，有那么一刻我很兴奋，我想让你告诉我......
I told you before starting the talk that I watched the Netflix series, there was a moment when I got excited, I want you to tell me...
Te contaba antes de empezar la charla que vi la serie de Netflix, hubo un momento en el que me emocioné, quiero que me cuentes...
这个想法是如何产生的以及是否容易说服您的整个家庭参与。
how the idea came about and if it was easy to convince your entire family to participate.
cómo surgió la idea y si fue fácil convencer a toda tu familia de participar.
而且还带着这样的报复的语气。
And there is such a tone of revenge.
Y hay un tono así de revancha.
我不会忘记你，不会忘记你，不会忘记你，不会忘记你，不会忘记我们所遭受的一切。
I do not forget about you, about you, about you, about you and everything we suffered.
No me olvido de vos, de vos, de vos, de vos y de todo lo que sufrimos.
他们为什么要说出这一切？
Why did they want to tell all that?
¿Por qué querían contar todo eso?
除此之外，当然还有来自其他地方的一项提案告诉您，看，我们想做一个......
Beyond the fact that of course there is a proposal that comes from somewhere else that tells you, look, we want to make one...
Más allá de que por supuesto hay una propuesta que viene de otro lado que te dice, mira, queremos hacer una...
关于你的生活的纪录片。
Documentary about your life.
Docuserio sobre tu vida.
是的，这个提议是他们两人提出的，他们就是来……的。
Yes, the proposal was from both of them, those are the ones who came to...
Sí, la propuesta fue de los dos, esos son los que vinieron a...
找我来做。
to look for me to do it.
a buscarme para hacerla.
我接受了，很明显双方......
I accepted and it is obvious that on both sides...
Yo acepté y es obvio que de las dos partes...
我们必须接受一些事情，同时也要付出一点
we have to accept things and also give a little to
tenemos que aceptarnos cosas y también dar también un poco a
彼此之间，他们想添加一些自己的东西，也
each other, they wanted to add a little of their own and also
uno al otro, ellos querían meter un poco de lo suyo y también
我的一生也都在我身后，对吗？
with my whole life behind me too, right?
con toda mi vida también detrás, ¿no?
不，我的家人...
No, my family...
No, mi familia...
简单，我告诉他们，他们必须出现在该系列中，他们必须出来说话，就这样，我的家人没有......
Easy, I told them that they had to appear in the series and that they had to come out and talk and that's it, my family didn't...
Fácil, les dije que tenían que salir en la serie y que tenían que salir a hablar y ya está, mi familia no...
他们不会制造任何问题，他们就像我一样。
They don't make a problem of anything, they are just like me.
No se hace problema por nada, son igual que yo.
很明显他们不喜欢相机，也不喜欢出去。
It's obvious they don't like cameras, they don't like going out.
Es obvio que no les gustan las cámaras, no les gusta salir.
但好吧，这是件好事
but well, it was something nice that
pero bueno, era algo lindo que
到最后这个想法和剩下的是什么，因为......
that at the end of the day the idea and what was left because the...
que al fin y al cabo la idea y lo que quedó porque la...
我们收到和拥有的数以百万计的消息
millions and millions of messages that we received and that we had was
millones y millones de mensajes que recibimos y que tuvimos fue
所有小孩，所有青少年。
of all little children, of all teenagers.
de todos nenes chiquitos, de todos adolescentes.
以及许多仍然想要实现梦想的伟大人物
and of many great people who still want to fulfill a dream and who
y de mucha gente grande que todavía sigue queriendo cumplir un sueño y que
由于某个人或另一个人的原因他们无法实现这一目标
that because of one person or another they cannot achieve it
que por culpa de unos u otros no pueden lograrlo
或者因为他身上可能发生上千件事情却什么都没有，这个想法是……
or because of a thousand things that could happen to him and nothing, the idea was...
o por mil cosas que le puedes pasar y nada, la idea era...
就我而言，就是为了能够证明这是可以做到的。
On my part it was that, to be able to demonstrate that it can be done.
De mi parte era esa, el poder demostrar que sí se puede.
中间有一千个障碍，你可能会多次撞到墙上。
that there are a thousand obstacles in the middle, that you can crash into the wall a lot of times.
que hay mil obstáculos en el medio, que te puedes chocar un montón de veces contra la pared.
会有人批评你，会有人忽视你。
There are going to be people who are going to criticize you, there are going to be people who are going to ignore you.
que va a haber gente que te va a criticar que va a haber gente que te va a bancar
并不是所有事情都总是美好的，我相信最终对我来说没有什么
that not everything is always rosy and I believe nothing in the end to me
que no todo siempre es color de rosa y nada creo que al final a mi
它对我很有帮助，我喜欢它，因为
It served me well and I loved it because
me sirvió y me encantó porque
不仅因为当我后来再次见到她时，我也哭了，因为我没有看到我的父亲、我的母亲或我的朋友发生了什么事。
Not only because I also cried when I later saw her again because I had not seen what happened to my father, my mother, or my friends.
No solamente porque también lloré cuando después la vi otra vez porque no había visto lo de mi viejo, lo de mi vieja, lo de mis amigos.
呃……
Eh...
还因为我告诉你我们收到的数百万条消息
but also because of what I tell you about those millions of messages that we receive
sino también por eso que te digo de esos millones de mensajes que recibimos
你不会相信我，但也有很多伟大的人
and you won't believe me but there are many great people too who
y no me vas a creer pero hay muchísima gente grande también que
他还写信给我们说他仍然想实现他的梦想。
who also wrote to us saying that he still wants to fulfill his dream.
que también nos escribió diciendo que sigue queriendo cumplir su sueño.
我什至可以告诉你，有人说我的梦想仍然是能够买一辆车。
I can even tell you that there were people who said my dream is still to be able to buy a car.
hasta te puedo decir que hubo gente que decía hasta mi sueño todavía es poder comprarme un auto
他们告诉我我已经 60 岁或者我 50 岁了。
and they told me I'm 60 years old or I'm 50.
y me decían tengo 60 años o tengo 50.
没什么，知道这一点让我感到自豪......
And nothing, it fills me with pride to know that...
Y nada, a mí me llena de orgullo saber que...
谁看过这个系列，谁对它有认同感，谁继续想要实现这个梦想。
who saw the series and who felt identified with it and who continue to want to fulfill that dream.
que vieron la serie y que se sintieron identificados con eso y que siguen queriendo cumplir ese sueño.
我在快 36 岁的时候就实现了这一梦想：成为世界冠军，并与阿根廷一起实现这一梦想。
I made it a reality at almost 36 years old, that my dream was to be world champion, it was to achieve it with Argentina.
Lo hice realidad con casi 36 años, que mi sueño era ser campeón del mundo, era lograrlo con Argentina.
只是因为
just because
porque sí
首先到达那里，然后一切都来了，一切都在工作。
Getting there first and then everything that came and everything is work.
Llegar a primera y después todo lo que vino y todo es trabajo.
一个人正在实现它，一个人正在努力实现它。
one is achieving it, one is trying to achieve it.
uno lo va logrando, va intentando lograrlo.
那么你一生都会有一些小梦想，而我的梦想之一就是
then you have little dreams throughout your life and well one of those dreams for me was that
después tiene pequeños sueños durante toda tu vida y bueno uno de esos sueños para mí era eso
他们打我，他们打我，我在地板上，他们一直打我，但我没有......
and they hit me, they hit me, I was on the floor and they kept hitting me and I didn't...
y me pegaron, me dieron, estaba en el piso y me seguían pegando y yo no...
不是我没有忘记，而是有人……
It's not that I don't forget, but that there were people who...
No es que no me olvide, sino que hubo gente que...
它让我比其他人受到更多的伤害，有些人因为他们的方式而伤害我更多。
that it made me hurt more than others, that there were people who hurt me much more because of their ways.
que me hizo doler más que otra, que hubo gente que me lastimó mucho más por las formas.
仅此而已，那就是来回，无论你喜欢还是不喜欢
and nothing more, then it's the back and forth, whether you like it or you don't like it
y nada más, después es el ida y vuelta, el que si te gusta o no te gusta
我留下了所有给我写信、喜欢它以及它在全世界产生的影响的人。
I am left with all the people who wrote to me, who liked it and the impact it had throughout the world.
Yo me quedo con toda la gente que me escribió, que le gustó y la repercusión que tuvo en todo el mundo.
您是否能够与您认为有过接触的记者交谈过？
Were you able to speak with any journalists with whom you felt that you had
¿Pudiste hablar con algún periodista con los que sentiste que te había
受到虐待？
Mistreated?
¿Maltratado?
不，不，不是真的。
No, no, not really.
No, no, la verdad que no.
并且有很多人...
And there are many who...
Y hay muchos que...
最近或在喝酒之类的事情之间有笔记
had notes lately or between drinks and whatever and that in
tenido notas últimamente o entre las copas y lo que sea y que en
桌上有些人曾在某个时候批评过我。
At the table were some of those who at some point did criticize me.
En la mesa estaban algunos de los que en algún momento sí me criticaron.
也许不是以如此糟糕的方式或以一种糟糕的方式，但就是这样，结束了，就留在那里。
And maybe not in such a bad way or in a bad way, but that's it, it's over, it's left there.
Y capaz que no de tan mala manera o si de mala manera, pero ya está, ya pasó, quedó ahí.
同样的回应，我对任何事都没有任何怨恨，这就是我要告诉你的
respond the same, I don't have any grudges about anything, that's what I'm telling you
responde igual, no tengo ningún rencor de nada, es lo que te digo yo
我和家人一起计划的系列是
The series that I planned with my family was
la serie la que yo planeé con mi familia fue
试图证明这一点，我很满意，因为后来的结果就是这样
trying to show that and I am satisfied because it turned out that way later
el intentar mostrar eso y me quedo conforme porque quedó de esa manera después
还有 Netflix 想要展示其他东西，好吧，一切都会导致一切，对吗？
There is also Netflix that wanted to show other things and well, everything leads to everything, right?
Esta Netflix también que quería mostrar otras cosas y bueno, todo lleva a todo ¿no?
你喜欢看那里还是和11一起看？
Do you like to see it there or with 11?
¿Te gusta verlo allí o con la 11?
是的，我喜欢它，我喜欢它，我喜欢它，因为我非常欣赏它，因为我喜欢它......
Yes, I love it, I love it, I love it because I have a very great appreciation for it because I love it...
Sí, me encanta, me encanta, me encanta porque le tengo un aprecio muy grande porque lo quiero...
我爱他就像爱我的兄弟一样，他是一个了不起的男孩。
I love him as if he were a brother, he is a spectacular boy.
Lo quiero como si fuese un hermano, es un chico espectacular.
我认识他很多年了。
I have known him for many years.
Lo conozco ya de hace muchísimos años.
好吧，其他人会告诉我为什么它来自中央，为什么它来自中央。
Well, others are going to tell me why it is from central and why it came from central.
Bueno, otros me van a decir porque es de central y porque salió de central.
这是我对他的爱
It's the love I have for him
es el cariño que le tengo
我在家里见过他一次，当时他爸爸带他来，他和我老人家一起打球。
I met him once at home when his dad brought him, who played ball with my old man.
lo conocí una vez en casa que lo trajo su papá que jugaba a la pelota con mi viejo
在那里我们拍了一张照片，时间让我们在巴黎见面。
There we took a photo and time led us to meet in Paris.
Ahí nos sacamos una foto y el tiempo nos llevó a que nos conozcamos en París.
我们在一起在俱乐部里，什么也没有，那是当它到达的时候，已经有很多年了。
that we are together there in the club and nothing, it was as soon as it arrived, it had been years.
en que estemos juntos ahí en el club y nada, fue apenas llegó, ya llevaba años.
我把他当作儿子一样，尽我所能帮助他。
I took him as if he were a son, I helped him in every way I could.
Lo tomé como si fuese un hijo, lo fui ayudando en todo lo que pude.
好吧，事实是，他接受了这件事让我感到非常自豪，因为好吧，我......
And well, the truth is that it makes me very proud that he accepted because well, I...
y bueno la verdad que me pone muy orgulloso que haya aceptado porque bueno yo le...
我告诉他是否想抓住它，他说是的，这让我很高兴。
I told him if he wanted to grab it and he said yes, it made me very happy.
Le dije que si quería agarrarla y él dijo que sí, a mí me puso muy feliz.
你正在独自喝咖啡，另一张桌子上坐着的是 Luis Fanjal。
You are having a coffee alone and at the other table is Luis Fanjal.
Estás tomando un café solo y en la otra mesa está Luis Fanjal.
他们进行眼神交流，然后……我付完帐就离开了。
They make eye contact and... I pay the bill and leave.
hacen contacto de ojos y... Pago la cuenta y me voy.
没有机会聊天。
There is no chance to chat.
No hay ninguna chance de charlar.
不，不，零。
No, no, zero.
No, no, cero.
聊天的机会为零。
Zero chance to chat.
Cero chance de charlar.
零，因为它不是...
Zero, because it is not...
Cero, porque no es...
他是一个人...
He is a person...
Es una persona...
我要告诉你的是，例如，我不喜欢参加那场世界决赛。
What I'm telling you is that, for example, I didn't like being in that world final.
de lo que te digo que por ejemplo a mi no me gustó ser en esa final del mundo
为了想要玩它的自我
that for the ego of wanting to play it
de que por el ego de querer jugarla
我不想伤害球队。
I wasn't going to hurt the team.
no iba a hacerle mal al equipo.
他有那个自我，他就是他他
he has that of having that ego that he is he he he
él tiene eso de tener ese ego de que es él él él
不，事实是我不是其中之一，但是......
And no, the truth is that I'm not one of that, but...
Y no, la verdad que no soy de eso, sino...
我不能再和这样的人说话了。
I can't talk to a person like that again.
No puedo volver a hablar con una persona así.
根据该团队成员昆·阿奎罗的说法，为什么俄罗斯会一团糟？
Why was Russia a mess according to Kun Agüero, who was part of that team?
¿Por qué Rusia fue un quilombo según Kun Agüero, que formó parte de ese equipo?
2018 年俄罗斯。
for Russia 2018.
por Rusia 2018.
为什么会发生这么多复杂的事情？
Why did so many complicated things happen?
¿Por qué pasaron tantas cosas complicadas?
好吧，一切糟糕的事情都是从一开始就开始的，从我们以足够的实力进入预选赛开始。
And well, everything bad started from the beginning, from the qualifying rounds that we entered with just enough.
Y pues arrancó todo mal ya desde el principio, desde las eliminatorias que entramos con lo justo.
有一天我们以一种方式玩，另一天又以另一种方式玩。
that one day we play one way, another day another.
de que un día jugamos de una manera, otro día de otra.
发生了变化，这个人玩了，另一个人玩了，一个人被选中了，一个人后来来了，另一个人来了。
that there were changes, that this one played and the other played, that one was selected, that one came later, that the other came.
que había cambios, que jugaba este y jugaba el otro, que se seleccionaba uno, que vino después uno, que vino el otro.
领带期间发生的一千件事。
a thousand things that happened during the tie.
mil cosas que fueron pasando durante la eliminatoria.
另外，他选择了兰奇尼，他们说一个即将到来，另一个即将到来，我不知道结果是什么
also that he selects lancini that they said that one was coming that another was coming that I don't know what that ended
también que selecciona a lancini que decían que venía uno que venía otro que no sé qué que terminó
看到另一个
seeing another
viendo otro
这总是喜欢问题、问题、问题
and that this and always like problems and problems and problems
y que esto y siempre como problemas y problemas y problemas
他们还告诉你的事情，你是无可争议的
things that they also told you that you were indisputable that it was
cosas también que te decían ellos de que de que eras indiscutible de que era
例如，正如我对自己说的......
For example, as I said to myself...
Por ejemplo, como me decía a mí...
是 Leo 和你，然后是其他人，你就是要在这里比赛的球员。
It's Leo and you, then the rest, you are the player who is going to play here.
Es Leo y vos, después el resto, vos sos el jugador que va a jugar por acá.
我不知道发生了什么，他突然把你带了出去，他没有向你解释，也没有
and I don't know what and out of nowhere he takes you out and out of nowhere he doesn't explain it to you and he doesn't
y no sé qué y de la nada te saca y de la nada no te explica y no
发生了一千件事，多么美好，最后……
a thousand things that happened, how good, that in the end...
mil cosas que pasaron, que bueno, que al final...
所有这一切都在导致一切变得一团糟，一切都不顺利。
All of this was leading, it was leading to everything being a mess, to nothing going well.
Todo eso fue llevando, fue llevando a que sea todo un quilombo, a que no salga nada bien.
因为那是世界杯，事实是
because it was the World Cup that it was and the truth is that
a que haya sido el mundial que fue y la verdad que
我们得到的价格相当便宜，因为至少我们达到了第八名。
We got it quite cheap because at least we reached the eighth.
la sacamos bastante barata porque por lo menos llegamos a octavos.
悄悄地，对我来说，我们甚至还没有获得通过第一阶段的功绩。
Quietly for me we had not even earned the merit to pass the first phase.
Tranquilamente para mí no habíamos hecho ni mérito para pasar la primera fase.
最后一场他们差点打成4比4平。
and they almost tied it in the last one, 4 to 4.
y casi lo empatan en la última, el 4 a 4.
是的，到目前为止，我们本可以有那么好的运气，但我认为不……
Yes, up to that point, we could have had that much luck, but no, I think...
Sí, hasta ahí, hasta esa suerte podríamos haber tenido, pero no, creo que...
由于事情的进展，我们很容易被排除在小组赛之外。
We could easily have been left out of the group stage because of how things were going.
tranquilamente podíamos haber quedado fuera de la fase de grupo por cómo venía todo.
因此，对于豪尔赫·桑保利（Jorge Sampaoli）来说，你也可以付账并离开。
So with Jorge Sampaoli you also pay the bill and leave.
O sea que con Jorge Sampaoli también pagas la cuenta y te vas.
不，不，事实是不。
No, no, the truth is no.
No, no, la verdad es que no.
不，没关系，没关系，是的，是的，是的。
No, it's okay, it's okay, yes, yes, yes.
No, está bien, está bien, sí, sí, sí.
不，没关系。
No, it's okay.
No, está bien.
我喜欢，我喜欢，是的，我想是的。
I like it, I like it, yes, I think so.
Me gusta, me gusta, sí, creo que sí.
不，因为事实是它并不......
No, because the truth is that it doesn't...
No, porque la verdad que no...
我不觉得我是一个人，我不觉得我是一个……我觉得……
I didn't feel like I was a person, I didn't feel like I was a... I feel like...
tampoco sentí que era una persona, tampoco sentí que era una... Siento que...
有时我觉得我已经克服了它，这就是
At times I felt like I was getting over it, which is
por momentos sentía que lo estaba superando lo que es
选择，压力，因为一切似乎都很容易，这很好
the selection, the pressure because everything seems to be easy, that it is nice
la selección, la presión porque todo parece que es fácil, que es lindo
一切从外面看起来好像没什么，但是
that everything looks like it's nothing from the outside but
que se ve todo como si nada de afuera pero
但到了那里之后，正如埃斯卡隆所说，必须做出决定，
But after being there, having to decide, as Escalón said,
Pero después estar ahí, el tener que decidir, como decía Escalón,
她还说，在巴西之后，她有点想离开。
She also said that after Brazil she kind of had that one that she thought she wanted to leave.
que contó ella también que después de Brasil como que tuvo ese que pensaba que se quería ir
我很清楚它就在那里。
It was clear to me that it was there.
Lo tenía claro que estaba ahí.
背后有很多事情，压力很大。
There are many things behind it, there is a lot of pressure.
Hay muchas cosas detrás, hay mucha la presión.
在这么多最终能进入国家队的球员中，很难只提及其中的 23 人。
It is difficult to have to mention only 23 of so many players who could end up in the national team.
Es difícil tener que citar solo a 23 de tanta cantidad de jugadores que pueden llegar a estar en la selección.
事实是，这并不容易，也没什么，我认为对我来说，他克服了一点点，好吧，什么也没有。
The truth is, it's not easy and nothing, I think that for me he overcame all that a little and well, nothing.
No es fácil la verdad y nada, creo que para mí a él lo superó un poco todo eso y bueno, nada.
就这样结束了
it ended that way
terminó de esa manera
你的表现比对阵德国的那场比赛更好吗？
Did you play better than in that game against Germany?
¿jugaste mejor que en ese partido contra Alemania?
2014年世界杯决赛结束后，7日，他联系了主教练马蒂诺。
After the 2014 World Cup final, on the 7th, he contacted Martino, coach.
posfinal del Mundial 2014, de 7, contata Martino, entrenador.
那天我看到你这样做，却直接下雨了。
That day I saw you do it, but it rained directly.
Ese día yo te vi hacer, pero llover directamente.
在那场友谊赛中他们以4比2获胜。
They won 4 to 2 in that friendly.
Ganaron 4 a 2 en ese amistoso.
我没听懂你的意思，开头就被删掉了。
I didn't understand you, the beginning was cut.
No te entendía, el principio se cortó.
如果你打得比那天更好，对我来说...
If you played better ball than that day, for me it's...
Si jugaste mejor a la pelota que ese día, para mí es...
我不知道你是否最好的游戏，但差不多了。
I don't know if your best game, but almost.
No sé si tu mejor partido, pero casi.
是的，事实是，那天我带着没有参加决赛的发烧而来。
Yes, the truth is that that day I came with the fever of not having played in the final.
Sí, la verdad es que ese día venía con la calentura de no haber jugado la final.
与必须去德国无关
and nothing about having to go to Germany
y nada el tener que ir a Alemania
世界杯结束后，他们赢得了冠军，我们必须与他们比赛
after the World Cup, that they had won it and that we had to play against them
después de la Copa del Mundo, que la habían ganado ellos y que teníamos que jugar contra ellos
可以说，这就像要摆脱它一样。
It was like going to get rid of, let's say.
Era como ir para que nos voluden, digamos.
所以，没什么，事实是我内心已经有了这一切，但最终它结束了......
So, nothing, the truth is that I had all that inside and well, in the end it ended...
Entonces, nada, la verdad que tenía todo eso dentro y bueno, al final terminó...
这最终是一场精彩的比赛，一切都出来了，一切都完成了，一切都完成了。
It ended up being a spectacular match where everything came out, everything complete, everything.
terminó saliendo un partido espectacular donde me salió todo, todo completo, todo.
而且赢了，对吧？
And it was won, right?
Y se ganó, ¿no?
但没什么，我感觉...
But nothing, I felt...
Pero nada, sentía...
所有这一切，看起来他们在那场比赛中搞砸了我们。
All that, it seemed like they were screwing us over that game.
todo eso, que parecía que nos estaban boludeando por ese partido.
我没能参加决赛，这就像所有事情都发生了一点……
I hadn't been able to play in the final, it was like a bit of everything and...
No había podido jugar la final, era como un poco todo y...
没什么，事实是我真的很想赢得那场比赛，所以事情才变成这样。
And nothing, the truth is that I really wanted to win that game, that's why things turned out that way.
Y nada, la verdad que tenía mucha ganas de ganar ese partido, por eso las cosas salieron de esa manera.
而且你也以7号的身份演奏，Leo不在场，所以乐队是你的。
And you also played as a 7, Leo was not there, so the band was yours.
Y además jugaste de 7, no estaba Leo, así que la banda era tuya.
是的，是的，是的。
Yes, yes, yes.
Sí, sí, sí.
啊，但是嘿，无论如何。
Ah, but hey, anyway.
Ah, pero bueno, igual.
当我和Leo一起玩的时候...
When I play with Leo...
Cuando juego con Leo...
感觉不一样，是别的东西，你知道他就在那里。
It feels different, it's something else, you know he's there.
se siente diferente es otra cosa sabes que está él ahí que
你总是有他的通行证，他总是监视你的动作。
That you always have a pass for him, that he always watches you for the movements.
Que tenés siempre un pase para él, que siempre te ve para los movimientos.
当他更多地在内线打球而我在外线打球时，我也感觉很舒服。
When he plays there more inside and I play on the outside, I feel very comfortable too.
Cuando juega él ahí más metido dentro y yo por fuera, me siento muy cómodo también.
我有最后两个问题，一个与系列有关，你玩过的怪物出现了
I have two last questions, one has to do with the series, monsters appear that you played with
Tengo dos últimas preguntas, una tiene que ver con la serie, aparecen monstruos con los cuales vos jugaste
以及曾经指导过你的教练。
and coaches who coached you.
y entrenadores que te dirigieron.
你曾经和你的队友组建过一支球队吗？
Did you ever put together a team with the footballers you were teammates with?
¿Armaste alguna vez un equipo con los futbolistas con los que fuiste compañero?
我不认为。
I don't think.
No se pienso.
你，10岁，里奥·克里斯蒂亚诺·内马尔，很难把它们放在一起，这就是为什么我告诉你......
You, 10, Leo Cristiano Neymar, it's very difficult to put it together, that's why I tell you...
Vos de 10, Leo Cristiano Neymar, es muy difícil armarlo, por eso te digo...
我不知道我们是否可以把它们放在一起，但你明白了。
I don't know if we can even put it together, but you get the picture.
No sé si ni siquiera lo podemos armar, pero te das cuenta.
你记录了多少？
How much of that did you record?
¿Cuánta de eso lo registraste?
嘿，看看我参加的比赛。
Hey, look at the race I did.
Ey, mirá la carrera que hice.
我已经多次问自己这个问题了。
I already asked myself this a lot of times.
Ya me lo preguntaba un montón de veces.
有些直播，我打了一个号码，因为我不知道该去哪里
some live and I hit a number because I don't know where to go
algunas en vivo y me pegué una número porque no sé para dónde salir
给你 11 分是非常困难的，因为......
It's very difficult to give you an 11 because...
Es muy difícil poder decirte un 11 porque...
我该把兹拉坦放在哪里？
Where do I put Zlatan?
¿Dónde lo pongo a Zlatan?
6个？
Of 6?
¿De 6?
如果只是说出下面的内容，这是不可能的。
It is impossible, if only naming what follows.
Es imposible, si ya solamente nombrando lo de adelante.
您已经有 6 或 7 名玩家。
You already have 6 or 7 players.
Ya tenés 6 o 7 jugadores.
我要遗漏什么，内伊？
What am I going to leave out, Ney?
¿Qué voy a dejar afuera, Ney?
我把伊布排除在外。
I leave Ibra out.
Dejo afuera a Ibra.
或者我忽略克里斯蒂亚诺或本泽马或梅西或凯利安凯利安
or I leave out Cristiano or Benzema or Messi or Kylian Kylian
o dejo fuera a Cristiano o a Benzema o a Messi o a Kylian Kylian
瓜鲁尼、瓜鲁尼、范佩西……
Guarruni, Guarruni, Van Persie...
我不知道，整合起来非常困难。
I don't know, it's very difficult to put together.
No sé, es muy difícil poder armar.
不，不可能给 11，不可能，事实是……
No, it is impossible to give an 11, it is impossible, the truth is...
No, es imposible de poder dar un 11, es imposible, la verdad que...
我非常自豪，因为这意味着......
I am very proud because that means that...
Me enorgullece un montón porque eso significa que...
我在职业生涯中做得很好，而且我有这样的机会。
that I did things well during my career and that I had that chance.
que hice las cosas bien durante mi carrera y que tuve esa posibilidad.
他们很少能和大家一起玩，因为我觉得……
that they have had very little to be able to play with everyone because I feel...
que muy poco han tenido de poder jugar con todos porque yo siento...
有时当他们问我这些问题时，如果你不问我，我就不会认为我在玩游戏
At times when they ask me these questions that if you don't ask me I'm not thinking I'm playing with with with with
por momentos cuando me hacen estas preguntas que si no me la preguntás no me estoy poniendo a pensar que juegue con con con
但每次他们问我时，我就像陷入现实并意识到......
But every time they ask me it's like I fall into reality and realize that...
Pero cada vez que me preguntan es como que caigo en la realidad y me doy cuenta de que...
我和大家一起玩
that I played with everyone and that
de que jugué con todos y eso
这让我非常高兴，因为不仅如此......
And that makes me very happy because not only that...
Y eso me pone muy feliz porque no solamente que...
我玩了一切，但我和每个人都相处得很好
I played with everything but with everything I got along very well with everyone
jugué con todo sino que con todo me llevé muy bien con todos
在球场上我完全了解自己
on the court I understood myself perfectly
dentro de la cancha me entendí perfectamente
这已经意味着一切。
And that already means everything.
Y eso ya quiere decir todo.
最后一个问题与中锋的第一场比赛有关。
The last question has to do with that first game at center.
La última pregunta tiene que ver con ese primer partido en central.
但你可别跟那个刚来的男孩说话
But don't you talk off that boy who's just arriving
Pero no te hablas off a ese chico que recién está llegando
这位玛丽天使正在对你说话
this angel of Mary speaks to you
le habla este ángel di María
谁知道发生的一切，好的，坏的，可怕的，光荣的，
who knows everything that happened, the good, the bad, the horrible, the glorious,
que sabe todo lo que pasó, lo bueno, lo malo, lo horrible, lo glorioso,
那个什么都不懂的孩子必须和他说话，可怜的东西，他说我即将实现我的踢球梦想。
And that kid who doesn't know anything has to talk to him, poor thing, and he says I'm about to fulfill my dream of playing.
Y le tiene que hablar ese pibe que no sabe nada, pobre, y dice estoy por cumplir el sueño de jugar.
一场头等舱的比赛。
a game in first class.
un partido en primera.
这位天使对那个即将进入中心的瘦子说什么？
What does this angel say to that skinny guy who is about to enter the center?
¿Qué le dice este ángel a ese flaquito que está por entrar en central?
享受。
Enjoy.
Que disfrute.
享受足球，这是世界上最美好的事情。
Enjoy football, it is the most beautiful thing there is.
Que disfrute el fútbol, que es lo más lindo que hay.
玩耍是一种独特的感觉，一种肾上腺素
Playing is a unique sensation, an adrenaline that
el jugar es una sensación única, una adrenalina que
那些退休的人会告诉你他们多年来的感受
that those who retire tell you what they feel afterwards for years and years and years
que los que se retiran te dicen que después sienten durante años y años y años
没有其他时间就像没有其他时间一样
that there is no other time like there is no other time
que no hay otra igual que no hay otro momento
并希望您充分享受每场比赛、每一次训练。
and that you enjoy every game, every training session to the fullest.
y que cada partido, cada entrenamiento lo disfrute al máximo.
一切都是后来的事，生活带你走这条路，上面的人引导你
that everything comes later, life takes you along the path, the one above guides you
que después todo llega, la vida te va llevando por el camino, el de arriba te va guiando
但最重要的事情以及我在赢得美洲杯后意识到的事情
but the most important thing and what I realized after winning the Copa América
pero lo más importante y lo que yo me di cuenta después de ganar la Copa América
不幸的是，这本来应该是以前的事情，但我必须享受这一点。
which unfortunately had to have been before, was the one I had to enjoy.
que lamentablemente tenía que haber sido antes, era el que tenía que disfrutar.
我必须意识到外面的那些都是木头做的，...
that I had to realize that those outside are made of wood, that the...
que tenía que darme cuenta que los de afuera son de palo, que el...
最美丽的事情就是踢足球，我们有这样的可能性
that the most beautiful thing is to play soccer and that we have that possibility that are
que lo más lindo es jugar al fútbol y que tenemos esa posibilidad que son
那些被重晶石触动过的人很少有可能有机会登上头等舱。
Few of those who are touched by the barite have that possibility of being in first class.
Poco de los que son tocados por la barite tienen esa posibilidad de poder estar en primera.
对于一名球员来说，最美好的事情就是在足球场上享受快乐。
The nicest thing that can happen to a player is to enjoy himself on a soccer field.
Lo más lindo que le puede pasar a un jugador es disfrutar dentro de una cancha de fútbol.
仅此而已。
and nothing more.
y nada más.
安杰利托，非常感谢你，很高兴
Angelito, thank you very much, it has been a pleasure
Angelito, muchísimas gracias, ha sido un placer
你是阿根廷国家队历史上最重要的球员之一。
You are one of the most important players in the history of the Argentine national team.
Sos uno de los jugadores más importantes de la historia de la selección argentina.
你已经赚到了。
You've earned it.
Te lo has ganado.
我希望我们就此结束。
and I want us to close with this.
y quiero que cerremos con esto.
这对你来说意味着什么......？
What does it mean to you...?
¿Qué significa para vos...?
赢得这个位置后，让人们谈论利奥、迭戈、斗牛士肯佩斯、帕萨雷拉。
having earned that place, let people talk about Leo, Diego, the matador Kempes, Pasarela.
haberte ganado ese lugar, que se hable de Leo, de Diego, del matador Kempes, de Pasarela.
的小鸭子，而且在那张桌子上，将有六，七名成员，你在那里。
of the filiol duck, but also at that table that will be six, seven members, you are there.
del pato filiol, pero que también en esa mesa que será de seis, siete integrantes, vos estés ahí.
我不知道，呃...
I don't know, huh...
No sé, eh...
对此很难说什么。
It's difficult to say anything about that.
Es difícil de poder decir algo de eso.
这是一种感觉...
It's a feeling...
Es una sensación...
独一无二，今天人们以这种方式认识我这一事实是很了不起的
unique, the fact that today people recognize me in that way is something
única, el que hoy la gente me reconozca de esa manera es algo
无法解释，这是我梦想的东西，我寻找的东西，我尝试的东西，我奋斗的东西
inexplicable, it is something that I dreamed of, that I searched for, that I tried, that I fought to be able to
inexplicable, es algo que soñé, que busqué, que intenté, que luché para poder
为了实现目标，不坐在那张桌子上，我认为坐在那张桌子上
in order to achieve the objectives, not sit at that table, I think that at that table
para poder lograr los objetivos, no sentarme en esa mesa creo que en esa mesa
这些可以在那里，其他的也可以在那里。
Those can be there as well as others can be there too.
pueden estar esos como pueden estar otros también.
但对我来说最重要的是能够给予
But for me the most important thing is to have been able to give
Pero para mí lo más importante es haber podido darle
阿根廷人很高兴能够看到 2021 年
that joy to the Argentines for having been able to see that 2021
esa alegría a los argentinos el haber podido ver ese 2021
当第一届美洲杯夺冠时，看到人们，看到幸福。
when the first Copa América was won, seeing the people, the happiness.
cuando se ganó la primera Copa América, ver la gente, la felicidad.
我有一次说过，人们只会说谢谢。
And I said it the other time, that people only say thank you.
Y lo dije ya la otra vez, que la gente solamente te dice gracias.
我说谢谢，因为如果我踢足球，我...
And I say thank you because if I'm playing soccer, I'm...
Y yo digo gracias porque si yo estoy jugando al fútbol, estoy...
做我喜欢做的事，我喜欢做的事，我喜欢做的事。
doing what I love, what I like, what I enjoy doing.
haciendo lo que amo, lo que me gusta, lo que disfruto hacer.
人们说谢谢你然后你意识到......
And people say thank you and then you realize that...
Y la gente dice gracias y ahí te das cuenta que...
阿根廷队正处于非常糟糕的时刻，赢得奖杯，给予......
that there are very bad moments that Argentina is in, that to win a trophy, to give...
que hay momentos muy malos en el que la Argentina está, que por ganar un trofeo, por dar...
其中一种乐趣是，当必须向别人表示感谢时，人们会说谢谢
one of those joys, people say thank you when that thank you has to be said to others
una alegría de esas, la gente te dice gracias cuando esa gracias hay que decírsela a otros
推动一个国家前进或实现这些目标，对吗？
to move a country forward or to achieve those things, right?
por sacar un país adelante o por lograr esas cosas, ¿no?
为了获胜。
For winning.
Por ganar.
比方说，为此喝一杯。
a drink for that, let's say.
una copa por eso, digamos.
对我来说，人们告诉你这些是很独特的，这是非常特别的事情。
For me it is unique that people tell you that, which is something very special.
Para mí es único que la gente te diga eso, que es algo muy especial.
我很自豪能够实现这一目标并且能够
and I am proud to have been able to achieve it and to have been able
y me tiene orgullo haber podido lograrlo y haber podido
近年来能够给阿根廷人带来如此多的欢乐。
been able to give so much joy to Argentines in recent years.
podido darle tantas alegrías a los argentinos en estos últimos años.
他们没有为我在桌子上放任何东西就是对他们的感谢
and for them to put nothing on that table for me is to thank them
y que ellos me pongan en esa mesa nada, es agradecerle
非常感谢，如果他们愿意的话，我很高兴能在那里……
Thank you very much, it makes me very happy to be there, if they want...
Muchísimas gracias, me pone muy feliz estar, si ellos quieren...
在那张桌子上，对我来说，最重要的不是坐在那张桌子上，而是
at that table and for me the most important thing is not to be sitting at that table but to
en esa mesa y para mí lo más importante no es no es estar sentado en esa mesa sino es
能够给他带来如此巨大的快乐，这不仅仅是一天
having been able to give him that joy so great that it will not only be a day
haberle podido dar esa esa alegría tan tan grande que no solamente será día
给他们所有人，但我也能够把它给自己，这是我一直以来的梦想。
to all of them, but I was also able to give it to myself, which was what I dreamed of so much.
a todos ellos, sino que también me la pude dar yo mismo, que era lo que tanto soñaba.
很高兴天使，再次非常感谢你。
A pleasure Ángel, thank you very much again.
Un placer Ángel, muchísimas gracias de nuevo.